（音乐照亮）
-[旁白]斯坦福大学。
-[老师]大家好，欢迎光临，
斯坦福CS193p 2020年春季。
这是第三讲。
我今天将从演示开始，
我们正在讨论的反应式SwiftUI内容的演示。
然后我要跳一些幻灯片，
多说一些Swift类型的系统，
具体来说就是协议，然后
之后一个完全不同的话题，
这是视图的布局系统，
它们如何在屏幕上布置。
如果时间允许，我实际上会做一些演示
到今天结束时，
如果没有，它将被推迟到下一次。
下次我们一定要布置卡片
行和列而不是全部
像现在这样水平排列
我们还将开始实际拥有
我们的模型玩游戏并实现我们的一些逻辑。
但是现在，让我们来做这个反应式Swift演示。
希望您现在对MVVM非常熟悉，
但是在我开始这个演示之前，
我要花一秒钟
复习一下，以防万一已经几天了
因为你做了功课。
这是我们的模型，称为MemoryGame。
它有这个不在乎CardContent
卡上有什么
作为模型，我们不在乎。
这取决于用户界面来决定它想要什么
在卡片上显示。
这是我们的卡。
这是此Card结构的数组。
这个选择让我们从本质上玩游戏。
我们还没有实现
但是当您选择一张卡时，
那就是匹配发生的时间，诸如此类。
这是我们初始化或创建MemoryGame的方法。
我们显然想指定
我们的游戏中有几副牌，
我们需要一个cardContentFactory函数
制作卡片上的内容
因为对我们来说，这不在乎。
因此，需要照顾的人必须为我们做到这一点。
这是我们的ViewModel。
我们的ViewModel有一个var，即Model。
我们的ViewModel可以一次与模型对话。
它是视图模型的门户或门口
因此它必须能够做到这一点。
请注意，这里没有指向视图的变量。
ViewModel从不与其视图对话。
与ViewModel对话的是View。
我们将看看
和ViewModel互动，只需片刻
但永远不会有任何连接
从ViewModel到Views
因为很多很多不同的观点
将使用此ViewModel，此门户，
这个门口，进入模型。
他们将使用它，共享它。
同样，这就是为什么我们的ViewModel是一个类。
它是指向堆中某物的指针。
分享指向的内容很容易。
因此，我们的ViewModel还提供了对模型的公共访问
否则是私有的。
而且访问都在获取信息，
喜欢拿卡
并让视图表达其意图，在这种情况下，
选择一张卡。
两者都非常容易通过我们的模型实施
但这就是我们的ViewModels工作。
最后，我们有自己的观点。
在MVVM视图意义上，我们的视图中有两个视图。
一个是代表一张卡片的视图
然后是此视图，这是我们在此处组合的所有卡。
根据我得到的反馈
你们中的一些人
在本周的家庭作业中，
我想澄清一点，我们的想法
通过澄清我们用来描述事物的词语。
你们当中有些人在说
“哦，我正在使用此功能
“设置卡的字体。”
虽然我认为这是不正确的，
真的更好的说法是
这个功能在这里修改了我们发送给它的视图
以便使用此字体进行绘制。
那有什么区别？
嗯，这是声明式编程之间的区别
和命令式编程。
在声明中，我们只是声明这是字体
用于绘制此视图，
而当务之急是，您在想诸如此类的事情，
我正在调用此函数来设置字体
在某个时刻，我正在设置它。
并且没有及时使用此声明。
在任何时候，这应该绘制视图
反映模型，它应该能够
随时要求该机构这样做。
景气，应该是一个视图
反映了模型的状态，
本质上对时间不敏感。
关于这个身体的另一件事是这个变种，
您永远不会访问此变量。
下半身永远不会出现在您的代码中。
该主体由系统调用。
每当系统想要
绘制一个表示该模型的视图，
它将调用此变量以获取该视图。
因此，这由系统调用。
您的工作是通过声明实现它
为视图提供了模型的当前状态
通过该门户ViewModel看到的
我想说的最后一件事是
有些人在这些ViewBuilder中
例如在ForEach中，甚至在ZStack或HStack中。
记住这些是ViewBuilders，而ViewBuilders很酷
因为它们是返回View的函数
而且他们确实允许这种限制
并且它们允许您仅列出视图而不是
将它们放入数组或其他内容中，您可以列出它们。
人们想在这里放一个变种，
var x在这里等于某物。
当然，您不能创建var
在ViewBuilder中。
无法在这些ViewBuilder中创建变量，
只是不允许创建var。
你是怎么做到的？
有两种方法可以做到这一点。
第一，您可以将vars放在ViewBuilders之外，
只是在正常的功能上
然后我可以在这里使用x
但是如果我现在就这样做，
我已经创建了这两行，
我不得不说返回ZStack，
没关系，我可以做到。
另一种方法，也许是更常见的方法
是创建另一个，假设这是一个Int，
计算属性，然后返回任何内容
您希望x为的值
现在您可以在这里使用x
它将仅使用此计算属性
计算它想要的x的值。
这就是我们处理的方式
基本创建局部变量
或我们在此处绘制所需的变量。
顺便说一下，这目前称为ContentView
因为那是我们开始的地方
使用Xcode中的模板。
Xcode当时不知道我们在做一个记忆游戏
因此将其称为ContentView。
在我们开始之前就想过
我会告诉你如何重命名
成为一个更好的名字。
现在您可能会想在导航器中执行此操作
使用此处的搜索和替换功能。
您可以通过替换此处来做到这一点，
然后您可以搜索例如ContentView
它会找到它所引用的所有地方，
那么你可以更换它
带有EmojiMemoryGameView之类的东西
或类似的东西。
但是实际上，这不是我们要做的。
如果我们要更改var或类型的名称，
我们将使用重构。
所以我们要做的就是压低
Command键，Command +单击。
当我们按Command +单击时，我们会在这里得到这个漂亮的菜单
我们可以跳到定义
类型或var之类的东西。
我们也可以重命名。
所以我们执行Command +单击，然后我们将重命名。
它向我们展示了所有地方
它发现了ContentView，
本质上与我们在此处进行搜索相同。
其中一些会改变，
你可以用这个小勾号告诉
事情只会改变。
因此，它将更改此文件名，
因此，它将要更改其名称，这很好。
这里显示了评论ContentView
但这不会改变。
您会看到它不是蓝色，而是灰色。
只是说，我发现了这个，
但我不会改变，因为我不确定
那真的是指这种类型
因为它在评论中
所以我们必须自己改变它。
这个var preViews将会在这里改变。
那实际上是我们滚开的代码
一开始显示我们的ContentView
在此处的灰色preView窗口中，
因此显然需要进行更改。
这是场景委托中的代码
我们实际上在创建记忆游戏的地方
然后将其传递到此顶级ContentView中。
因此，当您执行此Command +单击并重命名时，
它实际上选择了Command +单击的内容
您可以输入新内容。
所以EmojiMemoryGameView，看看，它正在改变它
在所有其他地方，虽然不在这里。
就是这样。
所以你就在这里点击这个重命名
它已重命名，甚至是名称
此处文件的名称已重命名。
我们可以回去修复这些东西
不确定，例如此处的评论，
说，这是我们的EmojiMemoryGameView.swift
实际上就是该文件的名称。
所以这只是重命名的一小部分
因为有时您会为类型或变量选择一个名称
然后你会决定，
我真的不喜欢那个名字，不是，
因为命名真的非常非常重要。
不能过分强调它的重要性
为事物取好名字。
因此，当您改变主意后能够重命名，
非常非常重要
但是，今天我们的话题将是这种反应。
我告诉你SwiftUI是反应式的。
反应是什么意思？
我的意思是，当模型发生变化时，
它们将自动显示在“视图”中。
目前，我们的用户界面还没有反应。
所以这是一个问题。
让我们看看如何解决该问题
并使其具有反应性。
我们不会在这里实现整个记忆游戏
与所有匹配的卡片。
我们只是要向前迈出一步
这就是我们要使卡片翻转的原因。
这是我们模型的一部分。
本质上，我们游戏逻辑的第一步是
拥有卡片，当我们选择卡片时，翻转过来。
所以我已经移到了我的模型代码
目前我们只说选择的卡片
记得从上次开始。
现在我想开始实际实现我的游戏逻辑
首先将卡翻转过来。
现在，您将对此进行查看，您会认为，哦，这很容易。
Card.isFaceUp等于！card.isFaceUp，对吗？
有人通过我们的卡
他们想选择一个参数
我只是要面对它
在这里被切换或翻转为相反方向。
这有一个错误是
“无法分配给属性。'卡'是'let'常量。”
这都是争论
功能本质上是让。
您不键入该让，但它们是一个让。
这是一个问题。
但这实际上比这糟得多。
这不只是让它出租。
这是一张卡。
卡是一种结构。
结构是我们上次谈到的值类型。
记住，复制了一个值类型
每次将其作为参数传递给函数时
甚至分配给另一个变量副本，副本，副本。
它总是被复制。
所以这里的这张卡是这里一张卡的副本。
新的ViewModel将其获取或分发给View
当视图获得时，它就是副本，
甚至一个副本。
所以这实际上不是阵列中的Card，
这是一个副本。
每次我们传递值类型时，它都会被复制。
所以即使我们可以做到
因为那个问题我们不能
基本上所有这些都是让
无论如何，这不会做对的事情。
这只会改变这个人
最多可以交换的空间无效
就在这里
因此，让我们在这里尝试完全不同的东西。
让我们尝试找出索引
该卡在此阵列中的哪张卡。
我要说的是letedIndex，
这将是Int类型，
我等于，我要对自己调用一个函数，
该卡的索引。
所以索引我要写一个函数，
这将是这张卡的功能。
所以我要找到这张卡
找出它在此数组中的索引。
因此，您具有的func索引将成为类型Card，
它会返回一个Int，而这个Int正在
成为该数组的索引。
现在也许我会说让letedCard，
这将是类型卡
在那个selectedIndex等于我的牌。
这听起来不错。
现在我可以说现在让我们翻转卡片，
isFaceUp等于！chosenCard.isFaceUp。
所以这似乎是个好主意，
我们将在一分钟内实现它，
但这似乎很棒。
现在，我们从阵列中取出卡
我们将其翻转过来。
但这也不会出于完全相同的原因而起作用。
当我们分配一个变种给这个选择的卡片时，
这等于将其复制到此处。
它将卡从阵列中复制出来。
所以即使只是做一个作业
到另一个变量将复制值类型。
所以现在您可能会喜欢，
我们要如何改变这个东西？
好吧，我们必须对其进行更改。
而不是在这里更改此副本，
我们将要更改此数组本身，
这一系列的卡片，我们将到达那里
并更改正确的卡
成为不同的FaceUp。
所以我们要去做。
仍然会做self.cards selectedIndex，
但不是这种间接的
通过将其复制的变量
我将直接拥有那个东西
FaceUp等于不是那个东西直接是FaceUp。
所以我要把卡片翻过来
直接在数组内部。
这里发生了几件事。
一，注意我要放点
在每次访问我的变量之前
和功能，我呼吁自己。
在大多数情况下，此自圆点是可选的。
通常我什至会说，不要把它放在那里。
这只是额外的提示。
但是，由于这个原因，我上次谈到
他们要去哪里
因此，即使在少数情况下您确实需要一个自圆点，
像这里，在我们的视图中实际上需要自点
当我们点击手势时，这个自圆点
如果你把它拿走，那就有错误了，
您必须修复它，还记得吗？
所以他们要把这个拿走。
当他们拿走那东西时，
那么您几乎无处需要自我标记。
所以在那个时候
我不知道是从现在起两个月后，还是不清楚，
WWDC是在六月初。
很多时候他们会推出新软件，
Beta软件，至少在那时
也许他们会解决的，我不知道。
我不在苹果公司工作
我不知道他们的计划是什么，
但我们确实知道它已被公开批准
摆脱这个自我点。
所以在这个过程中
仅在本课程剩下的七八周内，
我有点推荐也许只是把自我点
在一切面前，因为它不会伤害任何东西
这样可以避免您遇到此问题
您必须在哪里进行修复。
您只是在学习这些东西
那会给你肌肉记忆
总是输入自我点
您必须训练自己
在此公共修复程序发布后的几个月内。
但这会让您在本季度摆脱困境。
那是我的建议
但是在您的作业中，我们不会说
哦，那是错误的，你把自己加了点，
或哦，那是错误的，您没有设置自我标记。
这完全取决于您。
我只是想为您解决可能的问题。
因此，自我推荐可能是我的建议。
但是这里有什么？
而且我们确信这会奏效。
我们确定要更改isFaceUp和该数组，
毫无疑问，selectedIndex的self.cards。
我们正在更改此数组以使其切换为isFaceUp，
但是我们这里仍然有一个错误，
“无法分配给属性：'自我'是不可变的。”
并不是说这张卡是一成不变的
因为卡不是，所以是变种。
如果放手，那将是一成不变的，
但这是一个变种，所以是可变的，
但是它本身就是一成不变的。
换句话说，我们自己的功能似乎
能够改变我们的自我。
如果我们做不到，那该怎么办呢？
好吧，这是怎么回事
我告诉你这些值类型
Swift没有做按位复制，
实际上不是在复制它们
从内存中的一个地方到另一个地方
当你把它们传过来时。
这就是语义
那就是你要想象它正在发生的方式，
但这实际上只是在内存中制作这些副本
当您开始更改我们在这里所做的事情时。
我们正在更改此数组，这是我们的实际属性，
所以我们不复印
实际上是在改变数组，
但是这种方法改变了我们的自我。
它改变了我们的自我，因为它改变了我们的牌。
所以我们必须通过说让Swift知道这一点
这是一个变异函数。
所以所有修改自我的功能
必须在结构中标记为变异。
这在课堂上是不正确的。
类在堆中。
我们有指向他们的指针。
我们总是可以更改堆中的内容，
总是通过指针修改事物，
正如我之前所说，
可以和一件好事一样是一件坏事。
但是对于结构，不，因为它们是值类型
我们必须让Swift知道我们正在对此进行更改。
现在，索引，我们将在这里写一秒钟，
它只是获取此阵列中Card的索引。
它实际上并没有改变任何东西。
它只是获取索引。
因此，它不需要或不想在这里进行变异。
同样或相反，
我们的初始化器隐式地改变了我们的自我。
我们正在创造自我。
我们在这里设置所有变量。
所以这当然是变异的
所以你不用说变异了。
所有的初始化都是变异的。
这都是值类型很酷的功能的一部分
Swift知道他们何时进行更改。
然后你会看到
除此副本外，还有其他好处
当我们复制事物时保持正确的行为。
卡的索引，我们如何找出
我们在哪里获得这张卡的索引
在这个数组中吗？
我们想要具有该卡的数组的索引。
事实证明，这对我们来说超级容易
因为卡是可识别的。
由于它是可识别的，因此我们只需查看其ID
并唯一地查看它是哪张卡。
所以我们只需要在这里做一些for循环
如果零点索引小于我们的卡数，
还是再一次，如果我们正在做自我点，
self.cards.count，无论哪种方式。
我只是要经历每一个
我要说如果自我点卡
在那个索引id等于
这东西在这里，
顺便说一句，我猜是两个等号，
那么我可以返回该索引，因为我找到了它。
在这里，我正在看我的数组
查看索引是否为该索引的Card，
它的ID与您传递的ID相同。
现在，您已经可以在这里真正看到一个问题了。
我们将这个变量称为，不。
我们不想这样称呼。
Of只是让它变得不错的东西
给打电话给我们说卡片自我索引的人。
这就是为什么我们要使用双重标签
外部名称，内部名称。
这样我们就可以将此卡号称为ID
但是呼叫者仍然可以说出卡片索引。
希望这是一个很好的例子，
完全明白为什么我们有外部名称
和参数的内部名称。
我们没有在这里做。
外部名称和内部名称相同。
这里有点争论
您可能实际上选择了下栏
因为很明显，我们正在选择一张卡
这就是这种说法的类型
无论如何我们还会选择什么？
但是我要这样离开，只是我们没有
更改我们的其他代码。
但是如果您阅读指南
作为上周家庭作业的一部分，
您会看到这是一个
那里可能有一个酒吧
然后人们会选择
并提供Card作为参数，
呼叫者将没有标签。
我们已经完成了for循环，我们找到了这个。
这里还在抱怨什么？
“函数中的期望返回Int缺少返回。”
哦，是的，如果这个for循环一直进行下去
却找不到那个卡？
然后我们必须在这里退货。
所以Swift实际上有一件很棒的事情
发生这种情况时返回这里
就像您去寻找东西一样，您找不到它。
在其他语言中，您可能会返回减一
或一些伪造的东西。
我想我会回来，也许你会归零
这是完全错误的第一个要素。
如果您去找卡，却找不到它，
你会说，好吧，归还第一张卡
即使您知道那不是卡。
所以我们现在回到这里并不重要
因为这都是错误的。
但是我要放一点东西
在这里叫一个TODO，然后说假的。
TODO是您以后可以回头的东西，
斜杠斜杠TODO，发现提醒自己
您需要解决此问题。
这些出现在顶部
它说索引。
如果您单击，这是我所有的变量和函数的列表，
看起来假货就在那里。
如果我单击它，则需要我进行虚假验证。
当我向您展示这种很酷的方式时，我们会回来的
你可以退还东西
就像我在Swift中找不到它一样。
我们将在下一次讲座中介绍
我们将修复此问题，我们将修复此问题。
但是现在，我们要在这里做这个假的事情。
所以我们有卡索引。
我们绝对是在这里翻转卡。
因此，让我们运行，看看它是否有效。
因为我们知道我们已经对此进行了连接
在那儿选择卡。
所以现在应该选择，例如选择卡片
然后将它翻转过来，就可以开始了
准备好了，鬼。
哦，南瓜。
好吧，这肯定是在这里访问模型
因为我们正在选择这张卡。
但是，这些卡为何面朝上呢？
这里发生了什么？
好吧，这是怎么回事
我们还没有实施反应式的东西。
我一开始就告诉你
这就是为什么我们今天在这里要做这种反应性的事情。
您会看到为什么我们需要反应堆。
我们选择了一张卡片，它去了这里并更改了型号，
它翻转了一张卡片
但是我们在用户界面中什么都没有看到。
而且在SwiftUI中永远不会是这种情况。
更改模型时，UI应更新。
我们如何做到这一点？
如果您记得我的MVVM幻灯片，
我在屏幕上放了一些关键字，然后说：
这些Swift关键字，我们将使用这些关键字
做这个反应，这就是
我们现在要做什么。
我们将从ViewModel开始。
这是我们的ViewModel。
以及我们使ViewModel参与的方式
在这种反应性的东西中使用约束
并获得称为ObservableObject的东西。
现在记住限制和收获，
也被称为协议。
这些限制和收获，我们在这里使用了一个，
冒号的观点，那是一种制约和收获。
我们有点受制于
实施这个机构
但是我们获得了所有其他功能
我们可以发送给View。
所以这是一个巨大的收获
因为我们的限制很小，请点击此处查看。
我们也在模型，卡片中做到了。
我们进行了约束并取得了可识别的收益，
这要求我们执行此var id Int，
但是现在我们可以分辨哪张卡了。
用户界面将在此ForEach中使用
确保我们的卡四处走动
我们可以跟踪它们的位置并为其设置动画。
您将看到SwiftUI中的动画非常简单
很大程度上是因为这种机制。
所以这就是制约和收获，
约束几乎没有。
您无需实现任何var或funcs，
没有身体或身份证或类似的东西。
微小的限制是它只能工作
对于类，使用ObservableObject。
如果您是班级，则只能在此处成为ObservableObject，
所以那是次要的约束。
现在，通过这样做您获得的收益
您是否获得了一个名为objectWillChange的变量。
这个变种在这里，你没有
像我们对身体一样放在这里
您可以在后台免费获得它。
所以这里不会。
我只是向您展示您所得到的。
而且这个var不是真正的这种类型，
ObservableObjectPublisher，
比这复杂一点。
我们甚至不知道或不在乎它是什么
但是我们需要了解有关此var的两件事。
一个是它是发布者，
意味着它可以发布给全世界，
对任何有兴趣的人，
我们的观点将会引起人们的兴趣，
当某些变化。
而且这个变数只能传送一个函数
这是发送功能。
如果您调用该函数在objectWillChange上发送，
即将发布给世界
关于这个对象，或者真的会很快改变
所以准备好然后对它做出反应。
就是这样，这就是我们要做的，真的，
让我们的ViewModel参与其中。
所以每次我们的模型改变时
我们想要做objectWillChange.send。
例如，这是一个意图。
显然，我们正在此处更改模型。
我们知道选择卡
是一个可变的变异函数。
因此，这当然会改变我们的模型。
所以在这里我们只说objectWillChange.send。
这是唯一的功能，真的，我们要调用
关于此对象将在此处更改。
这将要发布到全世界，
objectWillChange表示此MemoryGame将更改。
就这样。
这并不是说它是如何改变的，它已经改变了。
这一点很重要
因为如果此ViewModel更改，
模型上的此门户已更改，
希望该门户需要的视图
重画自己。
我们将在短短一秒钟内告诉您
他们如何注册才能做到这一点。
再说一次，我们不需要把它放在这里，
我们免费获得它。
而当我摆脱它时，您将看不到任何错误。
这完全是合法的。
您可以随时拨打此电话，
任何时候改变。
甚至不必改变您的模型。
例如，如果您要更改这些表情符号，
您可以完全由您来调用objectWillChange。
但是，在重要的应用中
您可能会有很多意图，
许多可能会改变您的模型的不同事物。
这有点烦人
不得不说objectWillChange.send，
objectWillChange.send。
甚至容易出错。
如果我哎呀雏菊忘了把它放在那里
然后您选择一张卡片，就像
卡仍然不翻转，为什么？
因为我忘了把它放在那里。
因此，尽管我们可以随时调用objectWillChange.send，
通常是我们处理这个问题的方式
是我们采用此var并使其发布。
所以这不是Swift关键字，
你会看到它不是洋红色的
这就是所谓的属性包装器
这是一个财产。
属性包装器添加了一些功能
周围的财产。
在这种情况下，这个包装器要做的是
每当此属性，模型发生变化时，
它调用objectWillChange.send。
这就是它的作用。
确实如此，要使我们的ObservableObject在此处，
我们的ViewModel会在每次发生变化时广播，
我们只需要@Published我们所有的变量
我们关心他们是否改变
在这种情况下只是我们的一个Model var。
也可能是其他事情。
你可以有很多
@发布的vars，如果想要的话。
任何时候只要他们改变
这将是objectWillChange.send，
这就是它的作用。
这看起来比记住要好得多
将objectWillChange.send放入所有这些函数中。
您仍然可以选择
即使使用这些，也可以执行objectWillChange.send
但是大多数时候你不会
做objectWillChange.send。
所以我们快到了。
现在我们有了ViewModel
因此每次模型更改时都会发布。
现在我们只需要在这里修复我们的视图
这样，当看到此ViewModel发布时，它将重新绘制。
每当看到这个东西时都会重画，
说出objectWillChange.send。
这样做的方法是使用另一个属性包装器
在这个称为@ObservedObject的对象上。
就是说这个var中有一个ObservableObject，
这样做，EmojiMemoryGame是一个ObservableObject。
并且每当它说objectWillChange.send时，都要重画。
当然要重画这一个
也会导致该笔重绘。
现在，您可能会觉得，
哇，这可能效率很低，
如果模型一直在变化，该怎么办？
我们是否会每次都重新绘制视图？
好，是的，不是。
是的，我们将对objectWillChange做出反应
和重绘，但是SwiftUI很聪明地看到了
是否确实发生了变化。
因此，如果我们翻转一张卡，
不会重提每张卡，
只是改变了，它知道
因为卡是可识别的。
您开始明白为什么这ForEach
在这一系列卡片上，我们不得不对此进行识别吗？
它有助于它了解这一变化
所以我实际上需要重画。
因为实际上是在调用此代码
可能不是很贵。
实际上是在屏幕上绘图，这非常昂贵。
因此，SwiftUI会尽一切可能避免这样做。
但是从概念上讲，这很简单。
每当我们的模型改变时，
这个@Published包装器注意到
我们是一个ObservableObject，因此我们的View可以标记
对那个出版感兴趣
瞧，这会重绘。
这就是我们进行反应式编程的方式。
真的，这就是全部。
我们将看到一些小的改进
做到这一点，但这实际上是它的工作方式。
因此，让我们看看它是否有效。
让我们运行我们的应用程序。
希望当我们点击卡片时，
我们会说选择了卡
但它们也将翻转过来。
因此，让我们尝试一下。
幽灵，我点击它，它正在双向翻转。
我让这个家伙，这个家伙，这个家伙。
好吧。
所以这里发生的是我们点击这些，
它是在onTapGesture上完成的。
它在ViewModel中表达了这个Intent。
然后，ViewModel询问模型
去做吧。
模型正在做这种变异的事情。
一旦完成了这种变异的事情，
很容易注意到这已经改变了
它被发布，objectWillChange.send，
这个家伙观察到那些objectWillChange.send
并正在重画。
那是我给你看的幻灯片，
来回，这就是代码中的样子。
所以我们现在需要跳回幻灯片
再谈一些协议。
一个协议会期待你
就像是精简的类或结构，
剥离下来，因为它具有函数和变量
但没有实施。
这是我制定的可移动协议。
它具有一个功能和两个变量。
var之一仅在hasMoved处读取。
您可以看到它带有大括号。
然后distanceFromStart
实际上是可读写的
这就是为什么它已经得到设置。
但是这里没有实现。
甚至那里的那些花括号，
那只是说这些变量是否是只读的，
这就是全部。
声明协议后，
现在任何类型，结构或类都可以出现，
是的，我要实现这一目标。
声称要实现该协议。
所以这里有一个结构轻便的东西
它在此声明中表示冒号Moveable。
当它这么说时，立即意味着
我注册实施
因此，它必须实现每个var
以及Moveable中的每个功能。
现在我们已经在View之前看到了
我们有ContentView，冒号视图。
它签约成为View，这就是为什么它拥有
做var body，同一件事是Card，可识别。
它签署了实施Identifiable的协议。
它必须实现该var id。
现在也可以说一个协议
它需要另一个协议。
这称为协议继承，
不要与类继承混淆
因为我们在这里只是在谈论协议。
所以我这里有一个协议载具
它是从Moveable继承的。
它在那里添加了自己的var，passengerCount。
因此，如果像汽车这样的课程出现在底部
它说，我签署了您的车辆，
现在它必须执行所有三件事
来自Moveable，它具有
来实现Vehicle的东西。
如果您是结构或类，也可以
声称实现多种协议。
所以这里有上课车。
不只是说这是一辆车
而且它是可移植的
现在汽车可能必须实现vars中的所有功能
在所有这三个协议中。
现在，协议就是一种类型。
这意味着可以使用大多数协议
在大多数情况下，您有类型。
例如，我可以有一个类型为Moveable的变量m。
那是m的类型，这是Moveable的类型。
那是什么意思呢？
好吧，如果我还有另外两个变量，
例如汽车和便携式汽车，它们都是汽车类型
然后输入PortableThing，然后我可以说，
m等于汽车或m等于便携式。
我怎么这么说
因为汽车是动车，
它实现了可移动协议。
实际上，汽车实现了Vehicle，Vehicle继承了Moveable，
因此汽车是可移动的。
这很棒，因为现在我有了这个变量m，
我可以开始发送它的功能，例如移动，
已经移动，因为我知道m是可移动的。
不管是那里的汽车还是PortableThing，
我们知道那些变量和函数
将被实施，因为您需要
如果您说自己是其中之一，就实施它们。
但是要注意一点，
你不能说便携式等于汽车。
那里的var便携式设备不是Moveable类型，
它是PortableThing类型，不同。
因此，汽车不是PortablePorting。
它们都是可移动的，但是汽车是不同的类型
而不是PortableThing。
我认为汽车是一门课程，PortableThing是一种结构。
因此，甚至没有同样的事情。
所以你不能这么说。
我可以说m等于所有这些东西，
我不能说他们彼此平等
因为Swift正在执行var的类型，
然后当我说便携式等于
变量的类型是PortableThing，
不要在此处输入“可移动”。
一种考虑协议的方式，
我已经在演示中提到了这一点，
是制约和收获。
我用它是因为它押韵，所以希望容易记住，
它是这样的。
所以我在这里有这个结构，特斯拉，这是一辆车，
因此它实现了所有这些东西。
实际上，它受到限制
实施车辆中的所有事物
其中包括“可移动”中的所有内容，
但是受到限制会再次发生
世界为车辆提供的所有东西。
现在，您可能会说，嗯，在这里稍等片刻，
车辆是协议，没有实现。
我们怎么可能在这里获得任何收益？
似乎我在这里遇到了所有限制，但没有收获。
好吧，关键在于关键字扩展。
在Swift中，我们可以扩展协议以实现。
我们只说扩展名，协议名称，
然后我们可以放函数
带有实现函数的vars中的实现函数。
现在我们不能在这里存储任何变量了。
因此有一个限制，它必须是计算的vars，
就像var body是经过计算的，请记住，
它在同一件事之后有花括号，
但是我们可以添加任意数量的东西。
随着车辆登记簿的扩展，DMV
现在是特斯拉和所有其他车辆
可以在DMV中注册。
换句话说，他们获得了这种能力
忍受他们所受的束缚
实现那些方法和变量
在那些协议中。
是的，这真的是中心
Swift中的函数式编程。
协议视图可能是
这样做的发帖者。
我们将看到更多关于View的信息
在这里有几张幻灯片。
除了添加功能之外，
像registerWithDMV一样，您也可以使用扩展名
如果要添加默认实现，请选择协议。
所以我在这里扩展Moveable
我实际上是提供默认的实现
for hasMoved as hasMoved是变量之一
在协议中
但是我在这里提供了默认的实现。
我只是在看我的距离
如果大于零，
我假设我已经搬家了。
而我正在通过对Moveable进行扩展。
因此，这使我有可能拥有一个结构，
我这里有一个叫ChessPiece的棋子，它是可移动的，
您可以移动棋子。
ChessPiece不需要实现hasMoved。
如果ChessPiece只是实现moveBy
和distanceFromStart，
那么它将成功实现Moveable
因为它将采用默认实现
从那扩展名那里。
现在，如果ChessPiece想要自己实现hasMoved，
可以，但是不必
因为有一个默认的实现
对于该扩展中的hasMoved。
现在，您当然可以使用扩展程序了，
还要向结构和类中添加代码，
不只是协议。
例如，在这里，我有一个名为Boat的结构
它有自己的方法，无论它们是什么。
在这里，我将扩展添加到Boat中，
一个功能sailAroundTheWorld。
您可以看到，该扩展名带有花括号，
它有一个实现。
这是sailAroundTheWorld的实际实现
我们已经添加到Boat中
您甚至可以制作类似Boat的产品
完全通过使用您的扩展协议。
所以Boat现在不执行任何协议
但我可以使Boat工具可移动
通过扩展到Boat
表示冒号Moveable，然后在该扩展名中，
实现moveBy和distanceFromStart。
现在船是可移动的。
我将其全部添加为扩展名。
这不是一件罕见的事
采取结构或类别并使其符合标准
纯粹使用扩展的协议
或者您将代码添加到扩展程序中。
为什么我们要做所有这些协议呢？
现在，对于那些即将到来的人
来自面向对象的编程
看起来就像是，这是怎么回事？
我们为什么要做这个？
嗯，有一个非常好的概念上的原因
为什么我们要这样做。
协议不包含类型，结构和类，
其他我们没有讨论过的协议，甚至枚举，
说出他们的能力，
他们可以做什么功能，他们有什么变量，
这也是其他代码的一种方式
要求其他物体的某些行为
通过要求他们遵守协议，
通过具有该类型的变量
他们正在尝试为函数分配或参数化。
您甚至还会看到其他机制
当我们谈论泛型和协议时
要求您希望该东西是可移动的。
无论如何，它必须是一辆载具。
现在，有了此协议，就可以要求它了。
但在所有这些方面，双方都不必透露
您是哪种结构类。
您完全可以随心所欲。
你只是说你实现了Moveable
现在您可以将其作为可移动设备进行操作，
但你可以是任何人。
您可能是汽车，也可能是PortableThing。
你可能是一条船。
我们知道什么时候双方都不在乎。
一方面，您可以做可移动的事情
而所有其他副作用是
它实现了所有那些可移动的东西。
这就是函数式编程
或实际上我们可以称之为面向协议的编程，
关于一切。
这是关于规范数据结构的方式
在我们的应用程序功能中，它们的行为方式。
即使我们在协议的上下文中谈论var，
我们没有定义它们的存储或计算方式，
我们甚至不说它们的存储或计算位置，
我们只是在谈论它们是只读还是读，写。
通过所有这些，我们专注于功能。
我们隐藏了实现细节。
这是最终的承诺
面向对象程序设计的封装
但这确实是一个更高的层次
因为它不会无情地混合它
有了数据和所有这些，
只是在谈论功能。
所有这些都变得更加强大
当我们将其与泛型结合使用时。
协议加上泛型等于
正如我在这里所说的，超级大国。
让我们来看看泛型
记住那是无关紧要的东西
我们上次谈到的
它如何与协议结合以产生超能力。
开始了。
让我们以示例方式进行操作。
假设我有一个名为Greatness的协议，
这个协议里面只有一个功能
就是比其他大。
此函数的另一个参数是GreaterThan。
顺便说一句，这是一个有趣的功能
因为其他类型是大写S Self。
这是协议中一种特殊的类型名称
表示实际类型
正在实施该协议，
因为请记住，协议本身
没有实现，他们就实现了
通过结构和类。
因此，Self表示实际的结构类
实现了这一点，当时正在执行它。
所以这很酷。
我要告诉你它是如何工作的
只需点击几下。
因此，如果我们有此协议，请看我们能做什么。
扩展数组，所以我要在数组中添加一些内容，
元素不在乎Array，
符合伟大，冒号伟大。
这样我放在红色的地方
因为这真的是关键
泛型和协议的连接。
在这里，我实际上要添加一个变量，
或者我可以通过功能来做到这一点
但是我要在这里添加一个变量
数组，以便每个数组元素所在的位置，
不在乎，符合Greatness会得到此var。
让它沉入。
现在，此变量将不存在于数组中
不在乎的地方
协议伟大。
该变量只是不会存在。
如果您尝试在代码中键入它，
编译器会说，
这个数组没有实现最大
它只会说它实现了最大
只允许您正确输入
如果它是某物的数组
实现了协议Greatness
现在我喜欢这样称呼，我们有点关心。
通常我们称泛型不在乎，
元素是不在乎，
数组不在乎其中的内容。
好吧，这有点
这个对Array的扩展有点关心元素。
真的不在乎什么元素
可以是任何结构或类，但我们会注意
它实现了伟大。
所以这有点关怀，
你想那样想。
然后，这个无穷大，看看它的类型是什么，元素。
不在乎，因为我要看
通过数组找到最伟大的那个
通过调用isGreatThan
在数组中的所有事物上
我知道我可以做，因为这个对Array的扩展
只是元素实现伟大的地方。
在这里看到一切如何？
您可以轻松想象，我不会在这里显示代码，
但您可以轻松想象构建一个for循环
只是涉及所有要素，
通话比所有通话都好，
找出哪一个是最大的
那只是返回它。
因此，让我们看看如何使用这样的数组。
假设我使用另一个扩展
使Int类型为Int
这是一个结构，实现伟大。
没问题，这很容易
实现一个比其他更好的Int，
只是我自己比其他Int伟大，
您可以使用大于
看看某物是否大于某物。
但是想象一下我有完全不同的类型。
这是总统的延伸。
那是美国总统。
我要让它实现伟大，
func比其他总统大。
我要实施...
其实我有唐纳德·特朗普，
来宾iOS程序员来实现这一点。
他说那比
只是self.name等于Trump。
如果是这样，那当然是大于，
他是一位出色的iOS程序员，每个人都告诉我，
我到处都听到。
所以我们开始，我们得到了。
现在，我想指出的一件事
关于您看到的这张幻灯片
这里是紫色的东西。
还记得顶部的“其他自我”吗？
还记得资本S Self吗？
看一下，当我创建这些扩展后，
自我变成了我要延伸的类型
我正在实现该协议的类型。
希望可以帮助您了解自我。
我提出这一点是因为有很多协议
在Swift UI中执行此操作的地方
或其中一种类型的功能
论据的关键是实现这一点。
因此，这并不少见。
所以现在我有诚信和总裁。
他们都实现了这个协议，伟大。
因此，我应该能够在它们上调用该Array var。
我应该可以使用Array var
我在那定义的最大，最大的东西。
因此，让我们看一下Int的外观。
所以对于Int，假设我有一个numbersArray
它是类型的Int数组。
我将在这里将其设置为等于常数Array，
我们在演示中看到了。
我们是用表情符号来做的。
在这里，我正在处理数字3、7和42
所以这只是一个数组，现在我可以说，
让foo等于numbersArray.greatest。
编译和工作是因为Int是
该Array和Int实现的内容
伟大的协议，所以最大的变种
因此被定义。
因此foo将是42，因为我们确实实现了它
只说更大一点。
我可以做完全一样的事情
如果我在这个数组中有一个总裁。
假设可以创建struct President
以总统的名字。
因此，我在这里创建了一系列总裁。
现在，我要说让foo等于
PresidentsArray.greatest。
那会把我还给我
或名字叫Trump的foo，
当然，基于他在此处编写的代码。
所以希望这能使您清楚
我们如何一起使用泛型和协议。
我们将在SwiftUI的所有位置进行此操作。
你们当中有些人正在看这一切，
就像我在这里所说的，我确定您正在发抖。
你必须要思考，圣牛，
我应该怎么知道
如何使用这项技术设计代码？
我的意思是，这对我来说是全新的。
这确实是一个非常强大的基础
对于设计事物，功能非常强大。
但是函数式编程确实需要一定的掌握
那只有经验。
好消息是您可以做很多事情
在SwiftUI中，大多数事情
无需真正掌握功能编程。
但是在这里，您正在斯坦福大学努力接受良好的教育。
所以我现在向你解释的原因
以便您在SwiftUI中使用它的次数增加，
您在文档中看到的越多
您看到这些商品在发生，
我们看到像View这样的协议
并且可以确定的是，
你不只是在说，我必须在这里放冒号，
你实际上是在理解
它是如何设计的。
而且您看到的越多，它就会越陷进去
最终您可能会开始变得更有能力
同时进行功能编程设计。
但是现在没有人期望你
能够设计东西
在其中添加协议扩展的地方
与泛型和所有。
但是最终您将能够。
同时，您会知道
SwiftUI中发生了什么。
所以我只是把这张幻灯片放在这里，关于枚举，
但是再一次，在本讲座中，我们将不再讨论枚举。
我们会尽快谈论，不用担心。
所以这几乎涵盖了我们要做的事情
今天谈论建筑
我们几乎涵盖了整个主题。
现在我要完全换档
然后转到一个完全不同的主题，即布局，
换句话说，我们如何决定
屏幕上所有视图的位置？
SwiftUI做到这一点的方法非常简单。
这是所有SwiftUI中最精美的东西之一。
确实只有三个步骤。
第一个是容器Views，
例如HStacks和VStacks之类的东西。
它们为内部的视图提供了空间。
然后，这些视图自行选择尺寸，
他们想要成为什么。
根据该报价，
他们可以选择与报价相同的尺寸，
这是最常见的
他们可以选择比报价要小的尺寸，
他们可以选择比报价更大的尺寸。
因此，它们以一种很好的封装方式使用
视图决定了它们的大小。
没有人告诉他们要多大。
他们决定，我们只是为他们提供空间。
但是之后，容器Views就像堆栈一样，
将视图放置在自己的内部是他们的工作。
就是这样，这是三个步骤
以便将所有内容布置在SwiftUI中。
因此，让我们深入了解一下。
让我们谈谈容器视图。
所以最常见的容器视图
您已经熟悉的是HStack和VStack。
当然，还有Zstack
这种堆叠在一起
但是HStack和VStack很有趣
因为他们将提供给他们的空间分开了
在所有子视图中
稍后我们将讨论其工作原理。
ForEach是一种不寻常的容器视图。
它实际上推迟了定位
并调整其所在容器的尺寸，
这就是为什么我们把CardViews
将ForEach放入HStack中。
因此，他们的ForEach正在推迟让HStack做出决定。
布局中隐藏着的一件事是修饰符，
例如点填充和其他。
它们本质上包含它们修改的视图，
如果你想这样想，
其中一些元素（例如填充）进行布局。
所以让我们再详细一点
关于HStack和VStack，最重要的一个
或至少是布局最多的一个。
堆栈划分空间的方式
提供给他们的情况是平均分配的
然后他们首先将其提供给最不灵活的视图。
那是什么意思呢？
因此，非常灵活的视图就是图像。
所以我们还没有谈论图像
但这只是一个显示图像的视图，
如您所想。
当然，它希望是图像的大小，
那种方式很不灵活。
所以通常图像会得到
他们首先要的空间。
另一个非常僵化的视图示例
文字不像图像那么僵化。
文字总是想自行调整大小
使其内部的文本可以理解
但是它确实可以缩小一点
并在文本末尾加点号
正如我们稍后将在这里讨论的那样。
因此，它不像图像那么灵活。
而且大多数视图都非常灵活。
例如，所有形状
就像我们看到的RoundedRectangle
无论您提供什么尺寸，它都差不多
并且它将以该大小适当地绘制自身。
因此，在其中一种视图选择了自己的尺寸之后
并采用所需的尺寸，
从空间中删除了那个大小
堆栈正在尝试分配
然后进入下一个最不灵活的视图
冲洗并重复直到所有空间用完。
就是这么简单。
这就是HStack和VStack分配空间的方式。
现在，在所有视图选择了它们的大小之后
然后HStack和VStack调整自身大小以适合这些视图
两者之间的间距很小。
HStack和VStack可以与任何View一起使用，
但是有几个
我要在这里介绍给你
确实有助于布局。
其中之一称为垫片。
因此，Spacer只是一个占据所有空间的视图
提供给它。
因此，如果您给它空间，它将使用该空间。
因此，它用于填充空间。
现在它实际上并没有画任何东西，
只是浪费了HStack或VStack中的空间，
这就是为什么它被称为垫片。
它具有minLength参数
这是应该的最小尺寸
在我们水平布置的方向
还是垂直，具体取决于是HStack还是VStack，
尽管我们通常不指定
因为默认值是正确的金额
在这个平台上的空间。
你要开始的一件事
习惯了本季度的发展，
即使我们专注于iOS，
您可以在Apple Watch和Apple TV上使用SwiftUI
间距和布局有些不同
在这些平台上。
SwiftUI真的很聪明地说：
我在Apple Watch上，所以我要用这么多空间
默认情况下在我的垫片中。
这就是为什么我们真正想要尝试使用这些默认值的原因
并且在使用Spacer时不指定minLength。
HStack本身也有间距
HStack间距。
而且我们不想那样做。
即使是填充，通常也可以放填充
但是如果你开始把数字放在那里
并像我们看到的那样指定确切的填充，
你在打败一点
此平台独立性的目的。
现在，有时您需要它，您只需
但是我们尝试尽可能多地使用这些默认值。
因此，另一个很酷的View可以放入HStack
或VStack是Divider。
所以分频器只是画一条分界线，
同样，特定于平台
这取决于分隔线的外观
在它的上下文中。
当然，分频器不像垫片
它不会占用所有的空间。
它仅使用足够的空间来绘制该线。
而且该线显然与方向相反
我们正在布局。
因此，对于HStack来说，分频器显然是
垂直线，对于VStack，
这将是一条水平线。
所以您几乎肯定会想要使用一个
或在下一个作业中同时使用这两种方法。
它们对于使用堆栈进行布局真的很有价值。
这些HStack和VStack，
我告诉过你他们是有选择的
它的哪些观点为下一个优先领域提供了空间
用这个最不灵活的东西，
但实际上您可以覆盖
使用此视图修改器layoutPriority。
这是一个HStack的例子
它的文本非常重要。
它有一张我们知道非常不灵活的图片，
因此通常会引起HStack的关注。
然后有另一个不那么重要的文本。
所以我添加了View修饰符点layoutPriority 100
我可以选择任何我真正想要的号码，
没关系，这是一个浮点数。
这不仅仅是默认的layoutPriority
这是零。
因此，当该HStack提供其空间时，
它将首先提供此文本空间。
那文本会说，
好吧，当然，我想变得这么大
所以我可以很重要地一直使用这个词
那会说，好吧，
好吧，没有其他高优先级的产品了。
可能还有其他数字不同的数字。
它以最高优先级开始，然后下降。
所以现在去做图像
因为它不如文本灵活，
图像获得空​​间，然后不重要的文本出现
以适应剩余的空间。
正如我们之前提到的
当文本没有足够的空间时，
它会在其中放点
或缩短文本以适合其实际空间。
它一直想成为它的空间。
它从不希望超出其文本的大小。
它总是想要确切的尺寸
但是如果被迫变小，
它知道如何做点点。
HStack的另一个重要部分
VStack的布局就是它们的一致性。
因此，假设您有一个VStack，即垂直的View堆栈。
如果这些视图自行选择大小
它们的宽度不一样。
所以它们不能全部填满整个宽度
这个垂直堆栈。
VStack也会左对齐吗
或将它们居中或使其对齐？
它怎么知道将它们放在哪里？
好吧，实际上有一个关于VStack和HStack的争论。
我们已经知道VStack
和HStack具有参数间距
确定视图之间的间距。
它还有另一个论点，对齐。
对齐方式以对齐方式为准。
例如，其中一个对齐向导处于领先地位。
现在，为什么要领导这里而不是离开？
如果我只想要这个VStack
使所有这些保持对齐，
我为什么不说左点？
实际上，不存在像点这样的东西。
点领导意味着拥有事物
在VStack中排列，以便其边缘开始
文字的来源
有时用不同的语言来文字
从右边移到左边，
像希伯来语和阿拉伯语。
因此，我们希望我们的VStack一般能够匹配
文字来自那一边。
文本基线也可以排列。
因此，HStacks，仅在HStack中才有意义。
您可以将其对齐，以使文本的底部，
即使它们是不同的字体，也会全部对齐。
对于您所熟悉的字体，有两个基准。
我不会谈论这个
但您可以与第一个文本基线对齐
或HStack中的第二个文本基线。
您甚至可以定义自己的东西
对齐对齐指南。
这超出了本课程的范围。
所以我们将使用点中心等内置的
通常默认的对齐方式是
把东西居中
VStack或HStack。
但也有顶部
和底部尾随这些东西。
可以想象，当您开始输入时
在Xcode，VStack对齐冒号中，
当然，Xcode会帮助您并告诉您
这些内置的东西是什么。
堆栈就是这样。
堆栈非常重要。
但是还有另外一件事，修饰符
像点填充一样，我说的是一种行为
就像是容器视图
请记住，点填充等这些东西，
他们返回一个视图。
您可能以为他们只是返回一个View
这样我们就可以再寄给他们
在它们上调用另一个函数，点groundColor
然后给我们一个View，
我们称其为点填充。
这给了我们一个View，并在其上调用了点字体。
因此，不只是给我们一个“视图”
因此我们可以在其上调用另一个函数。
那些返回的视图实际上可能正在参与
在布局中。
现在，大多数人不参加，
像font和foregroundColor。
它们不会影响布局，因此可以提供任何空间
通过HStack或其他容器，
他们只是将其传递给包含的任何视图。
为了这张幻灯片的目的，我们将认为
这些修饰符被修改为包含的视图的外观
根据该视图，修饰符返回的是它的种类。
我们将在下周看到如何制作这些视图修饰符，
大概还是下一周，取决于情况如何。
你会看到那种真的
发生的是它包含
正在修改的视图。
这些实际参与的修饰符呢？
在布局过程中像填充。
让我们看一下填充。
点填充，此修饰符返回的视图，
它提供了它正在修改空间的视图
与提供的尺寸相同
但在这种情况下降低了10分，
无论填充是什么。
如果那10个不存在，
那么它将是任何适合系统的填充。
基本上是删除那10个
因为它知道应该提供10。
然后返回该视图
通过填充选择自己的尺寸
东西大小
它正在修改最终是加10。
这就是填充的作用
它在外面增加了10点
或您所说的任何优势。
另一件事是修改。
因此，您将看到点填充修饰符只是一个视图
参与布局。
另一个例子是什么？
您已经在作业中使用了它，
点宽高比。
点AspectRatio修饰符返回的View，
它占用了提供的空间
并自行选择大小
小于提供的尺寸
并具有长宽比，
那就是如果我们选择AspectRatio的点拟合选项，
或者它可能大于所提供的大小，
这是使用所有提供的空间的点填充选项。
因此，是的，当您使用View时，
当您有一定的空间时，
您可以选择更大的尺寸。
现在很少见了。
我们通常不希望Views溢出
互相贯穿，但这是有道理的，
像在这方面比率填充，也许这是有道理的。
因此，现在调整自身大小的AspectRatio视图
具有长宽比，提供它选择的空间
修改它的任何视图，例如CardView。
这样我们的CardView就适合自己了
在那个不错的宽高比空间中。
我们来看一个完整布局的例子
在传递的大小之类的东西上。
所以这是一个类似于我们的HStack
在我们的记忆游戏中，并不完全相同
但非常相似
这个东西的空间如何分配？
好，首先要了解的是
将提供空间的第一个视图
整个绿色元素就是填充视图。
这是最外面的视图。
最终，实际上就是视图
但无论有多少空间都会提供
对于这里的整个绿色建筑。
现在要做的是减少
从它的边缘拿走10分
并将剩下的空间传递到下一个视图
这是前景色修改器返回的视图。
现在，修饰符并没有真正参与布局，
确实对尺寸没有任何影响
摆好东西
因此它只是将其原封不动地传递给HStack。
现在，众所周知，HStack是大型布局视图。
它将开始平均分配其空间
由于aspectRatio不是像Images这样的东西
或固定大小的文字，
最终将空间平均分配
在ForEach的所有AspectRatio视图中，
因为我们知道ForEach本身就顺应了
到HStack。
所以现在是aspectRatio Views
正在HStack中进行布局。
每个aspectRatio视图将设置其宽度
占HStack宽度的份额
然后选择与宽高比匹配的高度，
2/3的宽高比，或者如果此处的高度受限制，
可能是相反的方式
其中aspectRatio视图占所有
所提供的高度，而是选择宽度
那不太适合。
因此，它可能以任何方式进行。
这取决于哪个最合适
在提供的空间中。
然后AspectRatio选择了该大小。
它将提供给CardView
而CardView将使用所有空间
因为就像普通的视图一样
无论您提供多少空间，它几乎都会被使用。
在所有这些提供和调整大小之后，
整个绿色视图的大小将是多少？
好吧，这将是大小
任何View.padding 10返回
这是HStack调整自身大小的结果
适合所有这些方面
在各方面加10分。
那将是整个绿色物体的大小。
让我们来讨论一下占据所有空间的视图
提供给他们。
显然，诸如RoundedRectangle，
对他们来说真的很容易。
他们只是一直沿矩形爬行到边缘
他们所提供的。
但是，像CardView这样的自定义视图呢？
我们使用ZStack构建的CardView
使用RoundedRectangle，Texts，我们正在构建此东西。
它占用了所有提供的空间，
而且没有理由不应该
但它确实应该适应自己
到提供的任何空间。
我们真的拼命地看到了这一点
带有表情符号的字体大小。
在你的作业中我问你
用于将很小的卡片切换为较小的字体。
而且我相信您可能会意识到，
哇，这真是解决这个问题的好方法。
当然是。
确实，在演示中我们需要做的是，我们要做的，
选择相关的字体大小
到提供的尺寸。
由于我们要接受提供给我们的尺寸，
我们应该选择适合的字体大小。
那么，视图如何知道为其提供了什么空间
并可以做出例如字体选择的决定？
好吧，我们使用特殊的视图来实现。
它只是一个视图，但是有点特殊，
称为GeometryReader。
以及您使用GeometryReader视图做什么
它包裹着您想要的任何东西吗
适应大小。
因此，这通常会吸收您体内的任何物质
您只需像这样将GeometryReader包裹起来即可。
GeometryReader只是一个视图。
我没有在这里向您展示显而易见的东西。
GeometryReader，开括号，内容，
冒号，所有这些，就像在HStack中一样
这仅仅是内容。
但是您确实注意到那里有一点争论
几何形状，类似于ForEach具有参数的方式
这就是我们要迭代的事情。
这也有一个论点。
因此，此参数的类型为GeometryProxy。
而这个GeometryProxy只是一个结构
它里面有一些很好的信息，
最重要的是您看到的第一个
var size，即您所提供的大小。
宽度和高度CGSize是宽度和高度
被提供给你。
您可以使用该尺寸，以磅为单位，
当然，字体大小以磅为单位。
所以对我们来说这很容易
选择适合该大小的字体大小。
你在这里看到其他一些东西，
像框架实际上不仅大小
但这是一个矩形
在某个坐标空间
我们的父母坐标空间或全局坐标空间
我们甚至可以看一下是否愿意。
我要谈谈那里的最后一个，
safeAreaInsets，在下一张幻灯片上。
关于GeometeryReader要记住的一件事，
它只是一个视图，但它始终接受
提供给它的空间。
我强调这是因为它需要一点点沉入
因为你不想在这里进入递归循环
GeometryReader正在读取其大小的位置
然后您尝试实际更改大小
基于GeometryReader读取的大小。
那样行不通。
GeometryReader始终接受大小，空间，
提供给他们的，
你必须这样想。
因此，GeometryReaders实用程序受到限制
知道您要提供的尺寸
并调整您的内在外观，
这就是GeometryReader的目的。
不要试图将GeometryReader变成不是的东西。
它只是在读取您的几何图形。
它叫做GeometryReader，它读取几何
并适应它，以便可以更改字体
之类的。
我们提到的安全区，
该safeAreaInsets
GeometryReader告诉您的信息。
通过思考可以最好地可视化安全区域
iPhone 10上的缺口
大多数时候，你不想草拟
根据缺口所在的尺寸，
并非总是如此。
有时您可能实际上想在那里画画。
还有其他安全区域的事情。
有时，视图会添加装饰
或他们在屏幕上绘画的方式
他们不希望您在某些空间中绘画的地方
因此他们会创建一个安全区域供您使用。
但是，如果您想离开自己的安全区域，则可以，
而你这样做的方式是
通过此处的View修饰符edgeIgnoringSafeArea，
然后指定所需的边缘
忽略那个安全区域。
因此，如果我说edgesIgnoringSafeArea回到顶部，
然后ZStack及其所有内容
忽略顶部有安全区域
然后就在那刻痕的下方画上去
因此，它可能是照片查看应用程序之类的东西，
也许你想一直到边缘
所以你可以在这里做。
让我们谈一点
容器如何工作
这是为其视图提供空间，然后定位它们的位置。
它为此修改器框架提供了空间。
现在，我在这里不再详细讨论框架。
你可以去看看文件架
有很多争论，你知道，
理想宽度，最小宽度，所有这些种类的东西
尝试与景观交流，这里是空间
我在给你。
这就是空间。
然后，视图选择了自己的尺寸后，
那么我们将使用这个修饰符位置
把它放在我们坐标空间的某个地方
在容器之前。
因此，他们就是这样做的。
非常简单。
例如，堆栈将使用其对齐信息
以及所有的间距
弄清楚他们的观点应该去哪里，
它会设置这个CGPoint
这是CGPoint视图的中心
对于每个视图。
顺便说一句，这里有点酷
称为偏移量，它将偏移视图
从容器放到哪里。
因此，您可以让容器完成其工作，
把东西放在某处
然后您仍然可以通过一些方式抵消它。
容器可以做到这一点
但其他人也可以做到。
视图可以做到这一点。
我想抵消一点。
因此，抵消是一个有趣的小家伙。
我们不用太多的偏移量
但我只想让你知道它的存在。
现在，为了记住，我们将使用框架和位置
创建我们自己的容器视图
有点像堆栈。
它被称为网格，它是2D，行和列，
而不只是水平行
这是一个非常可悲的游戏，
如果我现在就这样说的话。
我们显然希望它是行和列。
我们将通过使用框架和位置来做到这一点
创建我们自己的容器。
所以我们今天要回到演示。
我很想有时间去做那个容器，
但是我们没有，第三节课结束。
我会做一个简短的演示
只是向您展示GeometryReader的工作原理。
而我们要做的就是我一直在谈论的东西，
使我们的字体，表情符号字体变大
使用GeometryReader提供给我们的空间。
当我在那里的时候，我可能会做一件小事
我要告诉你最好的方法
或我们大家都同意的那种方式
在我们的代码中收集魔术数字。
如果您已经有一个如cornerRadius 10这样的设备，
那10是个魔术数字，
它确实不应该嵌入我们的代码中。
Swift中有一种规范的方式
把它拿出来放在自己的小空间
因此，它有充分的文档记录和类型。
现在，我们开始下一个演讲，
使用GeometryReader以及带有协议的泛型
和功能作为类型
使这个美丽的小简单的网格视图
那就像是一个HStack。
我们将仅使用此Grid View来替换HStack
并使我们的卡片排列在一个漂亮的网格中
因此，让我们跳入该演示
然后这将是本讲座的结尾。
现在，您在作业中被问到
在这里调整字体选择
适合小卡片，因为小卡片，
我们选择的字体，大标题太大。
这可能已经解决了，仅适用于小卡片
但是我让你这样做几乎是为了意识到，
好吧，那不是一个好的解决方案，
特别是当我们在风景中
甚至大标题也太小了。
所以我们真正想要的是我们的卡
选择使用所有空间的字体。
那确实是我们想要做的。
那么我们该怎么做呢？
好吧，我们将使用特殊的View来做到这一点。
这是另一个视图，就像HStack是一个视图
ForEach是一个视图，ZStack是几个，Text是一个视图。
这些都是视图。
有一个特殊的视图称为
GeometryReader视图。
所以GeometryReader有一个参数
这是要去的内容
显示在自己的内部
就像我们的名片一样，
ZStack可以制作我们的卡，
但是这里有一个很好的论点，叫做几何
就像ForEach是在这里有论点的View
但它也有这种内容论点
它提供了要遍历的Card。
同样，GeometryReader，它具有内容，
要求一个视图，但它提供了这种特殊的几何形状。
我们将看看这个小变量
在这里给你的
因为我们可以看一下
我们视图的大小是多少。
现在请注意，当我们放置代码时，我们的ZStack
在GeometryReader内容中，
我们得到了这些需要自我加点的东西。
因此，请通过此处并对此进行修复，
修理那个，捡起来。
那是什么
让我们看一下GeometryReader的文档。
因此，我将执行Option +单击以查看GeometryReader。
您可以在这里看到struct GeometryReader结构。
不用管它叫Content
该内容是一个视图。
所以现在，希望您开始了
了解这意味着什么，
内容是视图在哪里，对不对？
内容不在乎，视图是协议。
所以我们已经把无关紧要变成了
好吧，我们有点在意吧？
我们关心的是GeometryReader的内容是一个View，
但是否则它可以是它想要的任何东西。
所以我要在文档中打开它
看看它怎么说。
这是初始化。
您可以看到它需要这一参数内容
您实际上应该在这里识别此语法
因为真的，它需要一个功能
返回此内容的内容不在乎，
我们知道实际上是我们关心的一点内容
Content Content View所在的位置，因此我们知道它必须是View。
这就是一个带有参数的函数
GeometryProxy，并返回此无关内容。
不用担心在那逃脱。
我们将在接下来的几周内谈论这一点。
因此，让我们单击此GeometryProxy
并查看其装饰。
在这里，您可以看到它具有
我们在幻灯片中讨论的事情。
现在，我将重点显然放在此处的尺寸上。
因此，让我们单击它。
您会看到大小只是CGSize，
它只有get，它是只读的。
只是要告诉我们宽度和高度
我们已经提供了绘制此视图的方法。
这正是我们想要的。
我们希望此几何尺寸就在这里。
我要去做的是
我的CardView拥有所有权
在这里设置自己的字体。
因此，它将使用字体。
因此，我不再在游戏本身中设置字体。
我让卡设置自己的字体
无论如何，这可能是更好的封装。
为什么我们在这里，
我们不需要像HStack这样的冒号内容
以及所有其他这些东西。
我们可以摆脱它，摆脱它
所以这看起来很干净。
所以我们想在这里做一个字体，所以写一些字体，
其尺寸基于该几何尺寸。
所以我要创建系统字体，
只是在这里制作系统字体的不同方法，
样式和大小。
所以我只是选择尺寸。
我想要一个CGFloat，其大小为磅值。
并记住字体的磅值是相关的
到点的宽度和点的高度。
所以我实际上要选择最小的
宽度到高度的
因为我不一定要依靠
了解我的长宽比是多少。
所以我只选择这两个中的最小值
确保我选择合适的字体。
所以这是最小几何尺寸宽度
以及几何尺寸高度。
所以我使用的是我们看到的那个大小变量
就在这里的GeometryProxy中。
也许我们可以尝试一下。
让我们选择一个字体大小
这是这两个中的最小值
然后看看它是什么样子。
因此，让我们运行它。
看那个。
这样的尺寸要小得多，甚至会更小。
但这实际上太大了。
那里太大了。
也许只是因为绘图点大小
不完全是字体的宽度。
它可能与高度有关，
但是我们也确实在边缘上做了一些笔触
也会占用一点空间。
所以可能我需要某种常数乘数
大概是75％，0.75等等。
而75％的人看起来确实不错。
大的时候看起来不错，小的时候看起来不错。
在完成第三讲之前，
我想在这里花点时间
谈论编码风格问题。
我很少谈论编码风格，
纯粹出于时间限制
但是这次我要提一下。
因为这有点塞古
我们将如何构建我们的View代码
使其更具可读性。
我担心的问题是这些幻数。
我们已经创建了这些蓝色魔术数字
并开始在整个代码中散布它们。
那不是很好的编码风格。
SwiftUI是声明性的。
我们实质上是在这里直接声明UI。
我们不是在调用函数来告诉它自己构建，
我们在这里宣布。
当我们这样做时，这些蓝色数字最终
是我们可以转动的旋钮
调整View的外观并使其正确。
好吧，现在我们的旋钮
散布在这里
如果我们能有一个控制面板，那真是太好了。
因此，我将创建一个小的控制面板。
我要在这里评论以标记它的绘制常数，
我要称呼它
并把我所有的绘画常数放在这里
就像vars一样，让和在我的结构上起作用。
而把vars和let
和功能在您的结构
清理或修复魔术数字
在您看来，非常重要。
您会看到大多数视图都有一些变量
并让我们在这里玩
使外观看起来尽可能整洁易懂。
因此，让我们使用这个想法来获得这些神奇的数字。
这些碰巧是常数。
所以我要用let。
记住，让我们就像var一样
因为let表示它是一个常数。
因此，让我们在此处进行转角半径cornerRadius的设置。
您可能会认为您可以说cornerRadius等于10
但这是行不通的，我将向您展示为什么。
如果按住Option键，请记住，
然后点击，它将告诉您声明
您点击的东西
就我们而言，这是我们的角落
并且已将其键入为Int。
请记住，如果我们说让var等于某物
而且我们没有指定它的类型，Swift会推断出来。
这里是看这十个
和引用，看起来像一个Int。
那不是我们想要的。
这些蓝色的数字都是CGFloats，
我们用来绘制的浮点数。
现在，我什至不能说10.0。
如果我这样做，并且按住Option键并单击，则认为它是Double。
这些不是双精度浮点数。
此Double结构与CGFloat结构不同。
因此，我必须明确键入CGFloat。
那并不一定是那么繁重或繁重，
提醒自己的方式很好
这些在这里画出常数。
让我们做其他的吧。
我们得到了edgeLineWidth。
我们还有一个常数
这个数字三，我们当然有这个.75
这真的像我们字体的缩放比例。
我将其命名为fontScaleFactor
这也是CGFloat，0.75。
现在我将这些放在这里，
我可以用这些替换所有的魔术数字
这将成为我控制面板上的旋钮。
因此，让我们这样做。
我们有这个。
我要复制并粘贴，使此过程更快一点。
在这里，这三个是这里的边缘线
这里的fontScaleFactor是这个.75。
很好
实际上，这也使这段代码很好看，
非常像英语
试图了解正在发生的事情。
但是，您会注意到它的引入
这里有很多错误。
它们实际上都是相同的错误。
这是可怕的显式自我点
使捕获语义明确。
我们可以，也许可以解决这个问题
然后单击此处，然后修复此问题
然后我单击并修复它，
但我要告诉你避免的窍门
在GeometryReader的这种常见情况下，这个自圆点的东西。
因此，每当您执行GeometryReader时，
里面的东西总会抱怨
关于这个自我点。
顺便说一句，ForEach也是如此。
里面的每样东西都会抱怨自我点。
并非每个视图都这样做
但是这两个确实很常用。
我要创建一个功能
我要称呼它的尺寸CGSize
它会归还我的身体，
这样就可以像某些视图一样
我可以使用一些View作为此变量的类型，
我可以让一些View作为此函子的返回类型。
然后我要把我的身体剪下来，
放在这里，然后调用此函数
在我的GeometryReader中，self.body
几何尺寸。
这段代码实际上清理得很好。
这是很合理的。
现在该代码不再嵌入
在这样的GeometryReader中
因此您不需要这些自我点。
所以我可以摆脱那一个
还有那个和那个
所有那些自我点都消失了。
更重要的是，我没有通过整个几何
到这个物体，只是尺寸，几何尺寸var。
所以在这里，我不需要说geometry.size。
现在这个geometry.size就是size，
我传入的这个大小。
这样使这段代码看起来更好
我几乎总是建议，
至少接下来的几个月
直到他们把Swift的自圆点变化放在那里
因此自点不再引起此问题。
这是没有此代码的真正干净的方法
担心自己的点。
您可以在ForEach中为项目做相同的事情
因为每个人都会造成
那个自我点问题。
我们可以在这里做另一件事。
在这里，我可以有一个功能
对于称为fontSize的字体大小，
它返回的字体大小也是CGFloat，
并将这段代码放在这里
这样就可以读取fontSize的大小。
您可能会认为这是一个非常简单的表达，
我真的不需要在这里将其变成自己的功能，
但是同样，您不能使它变得太简单。
您真的想让它尽可能简单。
有时您不得不使其变得简单。
正如我所解释的，
不能是任意复杂的表达式。
所以有时候这需要一个函数
返回布尔，在这种情况下，
因为这是简单的布尔。
但是让这些小班轮发挥作用
使这个身体看起来更干净，非常普遍。
在这里，我们甚至可能没有
使这个fontScaleFactor成为其自己的单独
因为您可以考虑字体大小
作为绘图常量的一部分。
这是给定大小的恒定字体大小。
这就是第三讲。
我们要马上潜回去
从第四讲开始，并继续进行此演示
并使我们的HStack成为2D网格。
我们将学到很多东西。
-[旁白]有关更多信息，请访问stanford.edu。
(illuminated music)
- [Narrator] Stanford University.
- [Instructor] Hello
everybody and welcome,
Stanford CS193p Spring of 2020.
This is lecture three.
I'm gonna start today with a demo,
a demo of that reactive SwiftUI
stuff we were talking about.
Then I am gonna jump into some slides,
talk a little bit more
about the Swift type system,
specifically protocols, and then kind of
a totally different topic after that,
which is the layout system for Views,
how they get laid out on screen.
If time permits, I'll
actually do a little demo
of that layout stuff at the end of today,
if not, that'll be pushed to next time.
And next time we're definitely
going to lay out our cards
in rows and columns instead of all
in a horizontal line like they are now.
And we'll also get
started on actually having
our Model play the game and
implementing some of our logic.
But for now, let's do
this reactive Swift demo.
You're all really familiar
now, hopefully, with MVVM,
but before I start with this demo,
I'm gonna take just a quick second
to review it just in case
maybe it's been a few days
since you did your homework.
Here is our Model, it's called MemoryGame.
It has this don't care CardContent
which is what's on the card,
which as a Model we don't care.
That's up to the UI to
decide what it wants
to show on the cards.
Here are our cards.
This is an Array of this
Card struct right down here.
And this choose lets us
essentially play the game.
We haven't implemented any of that yet
but when you choose a card,
that's when the matching
happens and things like that.
And here's how we initialize
or create our MemoryGame.
We obviously wanna specify
how many pairs of cards in our game,
and we need a
cardContentFactory function here
to make the content that's on the card
because for us, it's a don't care.
So somebody who does care
has to make that for us.
And here's our ViewModel.
Our ViewModel has a
var which is the Model.
Our ViewModel can talk
to the Model all at once.
It's a portal or doorway
onto the Model for the View
so it has to be able to do that.
Notice that there are no vars
in here to point to the View.
The ViewModel never talks to its View.
It's the View that talks to the ViewModel.
And we're gonna see how the View
and the ViewModel kind of
Interact in just a moment here,
but there's never gonna
be any connectivity
from the ViewModel to the Views
because many, many different Views
will be using this ViewModel, this portal,
this doorway, onto the Model.
They'll be using it, sharing it.
Again, that's why our
ViewModel is a class.
It's a pointer into something in the heap.
It's easy to share
something that's pointed to.
So our ViewModel also provides
public access to the Model
which is otherwise private.
And that access is both
getting information,
like getting the cards
and also letting the View
express its Intent, in this case,
to choose a card.
Both very easily implemented
by us with our Model
but this is what our ViewModels job is.
And finally we have our View.
We have two Views in our
View in the MVVM View sense.
One is a View that
represents a single card
and then this View, which is
all of our cards combined here.
And based on the feedback that I got
from some of you working
on your homework assignments this week,
I wanna clarify a little bit, our thinking
by clarifying the words
we use to describe things.
A number of you were saying things like,
"Oh, I'm using this function
"to set the font of my card."
And while I guess that's
not exactly not right,
really a better way of saying it is that
this function right here
modifies the View we send it to
so that it uses this font to draw.
And what's the difference there?
Well, it's the difference
between declarative programming
and imperative programming.
In declarative we're just
declaring that this is the font
that is used to draw this View,
whereas in imperative,
you're thinking things like,
I'm calling this function to set the font
at a certain moment in
time, I'm setting it.
And there's no moment in
time with this declarative.
At any moment in time,
this should draw the View
that reflects the Model
and it should be able
to do that any time
this body is requested.
Boom, it should be a View
that reflects the state of the Model,
essentially time insensitive.
One other thing about this
body is that this var,
you never access this var.
This lower body is never
gonna appear in your code.
This body is called by the system.
Every time the system wants
to draw a View of the
Model that this represents,
it will call this var to get that View.
So this is called by the system.
Your job is to implement it by declaring
what the View is given the
current state of the Model
that you see through this
portal, the ViewModel.
And the last thing I wanna talk about is
some people were inside
these ViewBuilders,
like in ForEach or even
inside ZStack or HStack.
Remember these are ViewBuilders
and ViewBuilders are cool
because they're functions
that return a View
and they do allow this limited if then
and they allow you to just
list Views instead of having
to put them in an Array or
something, you can list them.
People were wanting to put a var here,
var x equals something down here.
And of course you cannot create vars
inside the ViewBuilder.
Vars can not be created
inside these ViewBuilders,
just not allowed to create vars.
So how do you do it?
There's two ways to do it.
One, you can put vars
outside the ViewBuilders,
just in your normal function,
and then I could use x inside here.
But of course if I do that now,
I've created this two line,
I'll have to say return ZStack,
but that's okay, I could do that.
Another way, and probably
a more common way,
is to create another, let's
say this wants to be an Int,
computed property, and
just return whatever
the value you want x to be
and now you can use x in here.
And it's just going to
use this computed property
to calculate the value of x that it wants.
So that's the way we deal
with essentially creating local variables
or variables that we need
to do our drawing in here.
And this is currently called
ContentView, by the way,
because that's the where we started
with that template from Xcode.
Xcode didn't know we were
doing a memory game at the time
so it called it ContentView.
Thought before we started,
I would show you how we could rename that
to be a much better name.
Now you might be tempted
to do this in the navigator
with the search and replace feature here.
And you can do that by
going here to replace,
and then you could search,
for example, for ContentView
and it would find all the
places it's referenced,
then you could replace it
with something like EmojiMemoryGameView
or something like that.
But actually, this is
not how we would do this.
If we're gonna change the
name of a var or of a type,
we are gonna use refactoring.
So the way we do that
is we're gonna hold down
the Command key, Command + click.
And when we Command + click,
we get this nice menu here
where we can jump to the definition
of a type or a var or something.
We can also rename.
So we do that Command + click,
and we're gonna go rename.
And it's showing us here all the places
that it found ContentView,
essentially the same thing as
we did the search over here.
Some of them is gonna change,
and you can tell with
this little check mark,
thing's just gonna change.
So it's going to change this file name,
so it's gonna change the
name of that, that's good.
Here it's showing the comment ContentView
but it's not gonna change that.
You see it's not blue, it's gray.
It's just saying, I found this,
but I'm not gonna change
that 'cause I'm not sure
that that's really referring to this type
since it's in a comment.
So we'll have to change that ourselves.
It's gonna change down
here this var preViews.
That was actually that code
we scrolled out of the way
at the very beginning
that shows our ContentView
in the gray preView window over here,
so that obviously would
need to be changed.
And then here's the code
in the scene delegate
where we're actually
creating our memory game
and then passing it into
this top level ContentView.
So when you do this
Command + click and rename,
it actually selects what
you Command + clicked on
and you can just type something new.
So EmojiMemoryGameView,
and see, it's changing it
in all the other places, not here though.
And that's it.
So you just hit this rename right here
and it has renamed it, even the name
of the file over here is nicely renamed.
And we can go back and fix the things
that it wasn't sure about,
things like comments right here,
say, this is our EmojiMemoryGameView.swift
which in fact is the name of this file.
So that was just a
little aside for renaming
'cause sometimes you'll pick
a name for a type or a var
and then you'll decide,
I don't really like that name, it's not,
because naming is really,
really, really important.
Can't overemphasize how important it is
to pick good names for things.
So being able to rename
after you change your mind,
really, really important.
Our topic today though is
going to be this reactive.
I told you that SwiftUI is reactive.
What do I mean by reactive?
I mean that when changes
happen in the Model,
they automatically are going
to show up in the View.
And currently our UI is not reactive.
So that's a problem.
And let's take a look and see
how we can fix that problem
and make it so it is reactive.
We're not gonna implement
our entire memory game here
with all the Card matching.
We're just gonna take a baby step forward
which is we're gonna
make the cards flip over.
That's part of our Model.
Essentially the first
step of our game logic is
to have a card, when we
choose it, flip over.
So I've moved over here to my Model code
where currently we just say card chosen
remember that from last time.
Now I wanna start actually
implementing my game logic
starting with flipping the card over.
Now you'll look at this and
you'll think, oh, this is easy.
Card.isFaceUp equals
!card.isFaceUp, right?
Somebody is passing us the card
they wanna choose as an argument
and I'm just going to have
this face upness of it
be toggled or flipped
to its opposite here.
And this has an error which is that
"Cannot assign to property.
'Card' is a 'let' constant."
Which it is all arguments
to functions are essentially let.
You don't type that
let, but they are a let.
So that's one problem.
But it's actually much,
much worse than that.
It's not just that this is a let.
This is a Card.
A Card is a struct.
Structs are value types as
we talked about last time.
And a value type, remember, is copied
every time it's passed as
a parameter to a function
or even assigned to another
variable copy, copy, copy.
It's always being copied.
So this Card here is a copy
of one of the Cards here.
The new ViewModel got it
or hand it out to a View
and when the View, got it, it was a copy,
maybe even a copy of a copy.
So this is not actually a
Card that's in the Array,
it's a copy of that.
Every time we pass a value
type, it gets copied.
So even if we could do this,
which we can't because of that problem
where this is all essentially a let,
it wouldn't be doing
the right thing anyway.
This would just be changing this guy
to its space up to be
swapped is having no effect
on this one right here.
So let's try something
totally different here.
Let's try and find out the index of
which Card in this
Array that this card is.
I'm gonna do that by
saying let chosenIndex,
which is gonna be a type Int,
I'm gonna equal to, I'm gonna
call a function on myself,
index of that card.
So index of I'm gonna write a function,
it's gonna be a function
in myself of this card.
So I'm gonna find this card,
find out what index it is in this Array.
So you have func index of
which is gonna be a type Card,
it's gonna return an Int,
and this Int is going
to be the index into this Array.
Now maybe I would say let chosenCard,
which is gonna be a type Card,
equal my cards at that chosenIndex.
It sounds good.
Now I can say now let's
flip the card over,
isFaceUp equals !chosenCard.isFaceUp.
So this seems like this is a good idea,
we'll have to implement this in a minute,
but this seems like this will be great.
Now, we are getting a
Card out of the Array
and we're flipping it over.
But this too is not gonna work
for exactly the same reason.
When we make an assignment
to a var, this chosen Card,
this equals copies this out of here.
It copies the Card out of the Array.
So even just making an assignment
to another variable copies a value type.
So now you're probably like, well,
how are we gonna change this thing?
Well, we have to change it in place.
Instead of changing a
copy of this thing here,
we're going to change this Array itself,
this Array of Cards, we're
going to reach in there
and change whichever is the right Card
to be the different FaceUp.
So we're gonna do that.
Still going do self.cards chosenIndex,
but instead of this indirection
through a var that would copy it,
I'm just going to have that thing directly
is FaceUp equal not that
thing directly isFaceUp.
So I'm just gonna flip the Card over
directly inside the Array.
A couple of things going on here.
One, notice I'm putting self dot
in front of every access to my variables
and to functions I'm calling on myself.
This self dot is optional in
the vast majority of cases.
And normally I would even
say, don't put it there.
It's just extra prompt.
However, because of this
thing I talked about last time
where they're going to make it,
so even in the few cases
where you do need a self dot,
like here, self dot is
actually required in our View
when we did our tap
gesture, this self dot,
if you take this away,
it's gonna have an error,
you have to fix it, remember that?
So they're gonna take this away.
And when they take that away,
then you're gonna need
self dot almost nowhere.
So at that point,
I don't know if that's two
months from now, it's not clear,
WWDC is at the beginning of June.
A lot of times they'll
come out with new software,
beta software, at least at that point,
maybe they'll fix it then, I don't know.
I don't work at Apple,
I don't know anything
what their plans are,
but we do know that it's
been publicly approved
to get rid of this self dot.
So in this course,
just for the next seven or
eight weeks left in this course,
I kind of recommend maybe
just putting self dot
in front of everything because
it doesn't hurt anything
and it'll keep you from
running into this problem
where you have to do the fix it.
You're just learning this stuff
and that's going to kind of
give you the muscle memory
of always typing self dot
which you'll have to train yourself out of
in a couple of months when
this public fix comes out.
But it'll keep you out of
trouble in this quarter.
So that's my recommendation
but in your homework, we're not going say,
oh, that's wrong, you put self dot,
or oh, that's wrong,
you didn't put self dot.
That's totally up to you.
I'm just trying to head off
possible problems for you.
So go for self dot is
probably my recommendation.
But what is in here?
And we were sure this was gonna work.
We're for sure changing
isFaceUp and that Array,
there is no doubt
self.cards of chosenIndex.
We are changing this Array to
have it isFaceUp be toggled,
and yet we still have an error here,
"Cannot assign to property:
'self' is immutable."
It's not saying that
this cards is immutable
because the cards is not, it's a var.
If it were a let, it would be immutable,
but it's a var so it's mutable,
but its self itself that is immutable.
In other words, our own
function doesn't seem
to be able to modify our self.
How do we do anything
then if we can't do that?
Well, what's going on here is that
I told you these value types,
Swift is not doing a bitwise copy,
it's not actually copying them
from one place in memory to another
when you pass them around.
That's the semantic,
that's how you have to
imagine it's happening,
but it's really only actually
making those copies in memory
when you start changing something
which we are doing here.
We are changing this Array and
this is our actual property,
so we're not making a copy,
it's actually changing the Array,
but this method changes our self.
It modifies our self because
it changes our cards.
So we have to let Swift
know that by saying
that this is a mutating function.
So all functions that modify self
have to be marked mutating in a struct.
This is not true in a class.
Classes are in the heap.
We have pointers to them.
We can always change things
that are in the heap,
always modify things through a pointer,
which, as I talked about before,
can be a bad thing just
as much as a good thing.
But for structs, no,
because they're value types
we have to let Swift
know we're changing this.
Now, index of, which we're
gonna write in a second here,
it's just getting the index
of a Card in this Array.
It's not actually changing anything.
It's just getting the index.
So it does not need or want mutating here.
And similarly or inversely,
our initializer is
implicitly changing our self.
We're creating our self.
We're setting all of our variables here.
So of course this is mutating,
so you don't say mutating in it.
All inits are mutating.
It's all part of the cool
feature of value types
that Swift knows when they're changing.
And you're gonna see that
that has other benefits
other than just this copy
on right behavior as
we copy things around.
Index of Card, how are
we going to find out
where this Card that
we're getting the index of
is in this Array?
We want the index into this
Array that has this Card.
This turns out to be super easy for us
because Card is Identifiable.
And since it's Identifiable,
we can just look at its ID
and uniquely see which Card it is.
So we just need to do
a little for loop here
for index in zero dot dot
less than our cards count,
or again, if we're doing self dot,
self.cards.count, either way.
I'm just gonna go through every one
and I'm gonna say if self dot cards
at that index id equals
this thing right here,
two equals, by the way,
of I guess, dot id,
then I can return this
index 'cause I found it.
Here I'm looking at my Array
to see if the index if
the Card at that index,
it's id is the same as
this one you passed.
Now, you can already see a
problem here of really of.
we're gonna call this variable of, no.
We don't wanna call this of.
Of is just something that makes it nice
for people who call us to
say self index of card.
That's why we have this dual labeling
of external name, internal name.
And that allows us to
call this card dot id
but callers still get
to say index of card.
This is a great example hopefully,
totally see why we have external names
and internal names of arguments.
We didn't do it here.
The external name and the
internal name are the same.
There's kind of an argument here
you might actually put the
under bar here on choose
because it's clear that
we're choosing a Card
that's the type of this argument,
what else would we choose anyway?
But I'm gonna leave it this
way just so we don't have
to change our other code.
But if you read the guidelines
as part of your homework last week,
you'll see that this is one
where maybe an under bar would be there
and then people would just take choose
and provide the Card is the argument,
there would be no label for the callers.
We've done our for loop, we've found this.
What's still complaining here?
"Missing return in a function
expected return Int."
Oh yeah, what if this for
loop goes all the way through
and never finds that Card?
Then we've gotta return something here.
So Swift actually has a fantastic thing
to return here when this happens,
like you go to find
something, you can't find it.
In other languages, you'd
probably return minus one
or some bogus thing here.
I guess I'll return,
maybe you'd return zero
which is the first element
which is totally wrong.
If you go look for the
Card and you can't find it,
you're gonna say, well,
return the first Card
even though you know that's not the Card.
So it doesn't really matter
what we'll return here for now
because this is all just wrong.
But I am gonna put a little thing
called a TODO here, and say bogus.
And a TODO is something
you can go back later,
slash slash TODO, and
find to remind yourself
you need to fix this.
And these show up up here along the top
where it says index up.
If you click, this is a list
of all my vars and funcs,
look bogus is right there.
And if I click on it, it
takes me right to bogus.
And we will come back when
I show you this cool way
that you can return things
like I couldn't find it from Swift.
We're gonna cover that
probably next lecture
and we'll fix this, we'll fix this.
But for now, we're gonna do
this bogus thing right here.
So we have index of card.
We are definitely flipping
the Card over here.
So let's run and see if this is working.
'cause we know we already
have this hooked up
to choose the Card there.
So now it should choose, say card chosen,
and also flip it over, there we go.
Ready, ghost.
Oh pumpkin.
Well it's definitely
accessing the Model here
because we're getting this Card chosen.
But how come these cards
are staying face up?
What is going on here?
Well, what's going on here is
we haven't implemented the reactive thing.
I told you at the start of this
that's why we're here today
is to do this reactive thing.
And you can see why we need the reactive.
We chose a card, it went
here and changed the Model,
it flipped a Card over
and yet we didn't see anything in the UI.
And never should that be
the case in SwiftUI ever.
When you change the Model,
the UI should update.
How do we make that happen?
If you remember from my MVVM slides,
I put some keywords on the
screen there and I said,
these Swift key words,
we're going to use those
to do this reactive and that's exactly
what we're gonna do right now.
And we're gonna start in our ViewModel.
So here's our ViewModel.
And the way we make the
ViewModel participate
in this reactive thing
is using a constrains
and gains thing called ObservableObject.
Now remember constrains and gains,
also known as protocols by the way.
These constrains and gains,
we used one over here,
colon View, that was a
constrains and gains.
We were kind of constrained that we had
to implement this body
but we gained all these other functions
that we can send to View.
So this one was a huge gains
for our very small
constrains to do View here.
We also did it in our Model, our card.
We did constraInt and
gains to be Identifiable,
which required us to do this var id Int,
but now we gain the ability
to tell which Card is which.
And the UI is going to use
that right here in this ForEach
to make sure that if our
cards move around or whatever,
we can track where they
are and animate them.
You're gonna see animation in
SwiftUI is ridiculously easy
and a lot of it is
because of this mechanism.
So this constrains and gains right here,
the constraints are almost none.
You don't have to implement
any vars or funcs,
no body or id or anything like that.
The tiny little constraint
is that it only works
for classes, ObservableObject.
You can only be an ObservableObject
here if you're a class,
so that's minor constrains there.
Now, the gain you get by doing this
is you get this var
called objectWillChange.
This var right here, you don't have
to put it here like we did with body,
you get it for free behind the scenes.
So this will not be here.
I'm just showing it to
you, what you're getting.
And this var is not really of this type,
ObservableObjectPublisher,
it's a little more complicated than that.
We don't even know or
care what it is really
but there's two things about
this var that we need to know.
One is that it's a Publisher,
meaning that it can publish to the world,
to anyone who's interested,
and our Views are going to be interested,
when something changes.
And this var can only be sent one function
which is the function send.
And if you call the function
send on objectWillChange,
it's going publish to the
world something changed
about this object or really
something will change very soon
so get ready and then react to it.
And that's it, that's all
we have to do, really,
to have our ViewModel participate in this.
So every time our Model changes,
we want to do objectWillChange.send.
For example, here's an Intent.
Clearly we're changing
our Model right here.
We know that choose card
is a mutable mutating function right here.
So of course that's going
to change our Model.
So here we would just say
objectWillChange.send.
This is the only function,
really, we're ever gonna call
on this objectWillChange thing right here.
And this is going to publish to the world,
objectWillChange meaning
this MemoryGame will change.
That's all.
It's not saying how it
changed, it changed.
And that's important to know
because if this ViewModel changed,
this portal on the Model has changed,
Views that are looking to that portal need
to redraw themselves.
And we're gonna show you in just a second
how they sign up to do that.
So again, we don't need
to put this in here,
we get it for free.
And when I get rid of that,
you can see no errors.
This is all perfectly legal.
You can call this anytime you want,
anytime something changes.
Doesn't even have to
be your Model changing.
If you were gonna change
these emojis, for example,
you could call objectWillChange,
totally up to you.
However, in a significant app,
you're gonna have,
possibly, a lot of Intents,
a lot of different things
that might change your Model.
And it's a little bit annoying
to have to say objectWillChange.send,
objectWillChange.send.
It's even error prone.
What if I oopsy daisy
forgot to put this in there
and then you choose a Card and it's like,
the cards still don't flip over, why?
Because I forgot to put that in there.
So while we can call
objectWillChange.send anytime we want,
usually the way we deal with this
is we take this var and
we make it Published.
So this is not a Swift keyword,
you can see it's not magenta,
it's something called a property wrapper,
this is a property.
And property wrappers add
a little functionality
around a property.
In this case what this wrapper does is
every time this property,
this Model, changes,
it calls objectWillChange.send.
That's what it does.
So really, to make it so that
our ObservableObject here,
our ViewModel, broadcasts
every time something changes,
we just need to @Published all of our vars
that we care whether they change
when in this case is
just our one Model var.
It could be other things as well.
You can have as many of these
@Published vars as you want.
Any time any of them change,
it's going to objectWillChange.send,
that's what it does.
This looks all a lot nicer
than having to remember
to put objectWillChange.send
in all these functions.
You still have the option
of doing objectWillChange.send
even if you use these,
but most of the time you will not have
to do objectWillChange.send.
So we're almost there.
Right now we've got our ViewModel
so it's publishing every
time the Model changes.
Now we just need to fix our View over here
so that when it sees this
ViewModel publishing, it redraws.
Redraws every time it sees this thing,
say objectWillChange.send.
And the way it does that is
with another property wrapper
on this one called @ObservedObject.
And that's saying this var
has an ObservableObject in it,
which it does, EmojiMemoryGame
is an ObservableObject.
And every time it says
objectWillChange.send, redraw.
And of course redrawing this one
is gonna cause this one
potentially to get redrawn as well.
Now, you might kind of feel like,
whoa, this could be really inefficient,
what if the Model is
changing all the time,
are we gonna be redrawing
our Views every single time?
Well, yes and no.
Yes, we're going to be
reacting to objectWillChange
and redrawing, but SwiftUI
is smart about seeing
whether something actually changed.
So if we flip one card over,
it's not going to redraw
every single card,
just the one that changed and it knows
because the Cards are Identifiable.
You starting to see why this ForEach
on this Array of Cards forced
us to make this Identifiable?
It helps it to understand this one changed
so I actually need to redraw that.
Because actually calling this code
is probably not very expensive.
Actually drawing on screen,
that's pretty expensive.
So SwiftUI does everything
it can to avoid doing that.
But conceptually for us, it's so simple.
Every time our Model changes,
this @Published wrapper notices that
we're an ObservableObject
so our View can mark
that it's interested in that publishing
and voila, it's gonna redraw this.
And this is how we do
reactive programming.
Really, that's all there is to it.
We're gonna see some minor refinements
to that down the road, but this
is essentially how it works.
So let's see if it works.
Let's go run our app.
Hopefully when we click on the cards,
we're gonna say card chosen
but they're also going to flip over.
So let's try the ghost.
The ghost, I'm clicking on
it, it's flipping both ways.
I'll let this guy and
this guy and this guy.
All right.
So what's happening here is
we are clicking on these,
it's doing this onTapGesture.
It's expressing this
Intent in the ViewModel.
The ViewModel is then asking the Model
to go ahead and do it.
The Model is doing this mutating thing.
Once it's done this mutating thing,
it's easy for this to
notice that this has changed
and it gets published,
objectWillChange.send,
and this guy observes
those objectWillChange.send
and is redrawing.
That is the slides that I showed you,
the back and forth, that's
what it looks like in code.
So we need to jump back
into the slides right now
and talk a little bit about protocols.
A protocol is gonna look to you
like it's a stripped-down class or struct,
stripped down because it
has functions and vars
but no implementation.
So here's a protocol,
moveable, that I've made up.
It has one function and two vars.
One of the vars is read
only there hasMoved.
You can see it has that
curly brace get there.
And then distanceFromStart
is actually readable and writeable,
that's why it has get and set.
But there's no implementation here.
Even those curly braces there,
that's just saying whether
those vars are read only or not,
that's all there is.
Once you have a protocol declared,
now any type, struct or
class, can come along and say,
yes, I'm gonna implement that.
That's claiming to implement the protocol.
So here I have a struct, portable thing
and it says colon Moveable
in this declaration.
And when it says that,
that immediately means
I sign up to implement this
and therefore it must implement every var
and every function in Moveable.
Now we've seen this before View,
we have our ContentView, colon View.
It signs up to be a View
and that's why it has
to do var body, same thing
Card was, Identifiable.
It signed up to implement Identifiable.
It had to implement that var id.
Now it's also possible
to have one protocol say
that it requires another protocol.
This is called protocol inheritance,
don't get confused with class inheritance
'cause we're just talking
about protocols here.
So here I have a protocol Vehicle
and it's inheriting from Moveable.
It adds its own var there, passengerCount.
So if a class like car comes
along at the bottom here
and it says, I signed up to your vehicle,
well now it has to
implement all three things
from Moveable and it has
to implement the thing from Vehicle.
You can also, if you're
a struct or a class,
claim to implement multiple protocols.
So here I have the class car.
It's not only saying that it's a vehicle
but also that it's
Impoundable and Leaseable
and now cars can have to implement
all the functions in vars
in all three of these protocols.
Now a protocol is a type.
That means that most protocols can be used
in most circumstances
where you have a type.
For example, I can have a
variable m of type Moveable.
That's the type of m,
it's a type Moveable.
And what does that mean?
Well, if I had another couple of vars,
like car and portable,
which are of type Car
and type PortableThing, then I can say,
m equals car or m equals portable.
Why can I say that?
Because car is a Moveable,
it implements the Moveable protocol.
In fact, car implements Vehicle,
Vehicle inherits Moveable,
and so therefore car is Moveable.
And this is great because
now I have this variable m,
I can start sending it
functions like has moved,
has moved because I know
that m is a Moveable.
And whether it's a Car in
there or PortableThing,
we know that those vars and functions
are gonna be implemented
because you're required
to implement them if you say
you're one of those things.
But one thing to be a
little careful of here,
you cannot say portable equals car.
The var portable up there
is not of type Moveable,
it's of type PortableThing, different.
And so a Car is not a PortableThing.
They're both Moveables, but
a Car is a different type
than a PortableThing.
I think a Car was a class,
PortableThing was a struct.
So not even the same kind of thing.
So you cannot say that.
While I can say m equals
each of those things,
I can't say they equal each other
'cause Swift is enforcing
the type of the var,
and then when I say portable equals,
the type of the var is PortableThing,
not type Moveable there.
One way to think about protocols,
and I've already mentioned
this in the demo,
is constrains and gains.
I use this because it rhymes,
so hopefully easy to remember,
and it works like this.
So I have this struct right
here, Tesla, and it's a Vehicle,
so it implements all of those things.
In fact, it's constrained
to implement all the things in Vehicle
which includes all the things in Moveable,
but being constrained on
that is going to make again
all the things the world
offers to a Vehicle.
Now, you might be saying,
well, wait a second here,
Vehicle is a protocol,
has no implementation.
How are we possibly
gonna gain anything here?
It seems like I got all constrains
here and I got no gains.
Well, the magic is in
the keyword extension.
In Swift, we can extend
protocols to have implementation.
and we just say extension,
name of the protocol,
and then we can put functions
with implementation functions
in vars with implementation.
Now we can't have any vars
that have storage here.
So there is that restriction,
it has to be computed vars,
like var body was computed, remember,
it had the curly braces
after the same thing here,
but we can add as many things as we want.
With this extension of
Vehicle registerWithDMV,
now Teslas and all other Vehicles
can be registered with DMV.
In other words, they gained that ability
by living with the
constraint that they have had
to implement those methods and vars
that were in those protocols.
So, yeah, this is really the center
of functional programming in Swift.
And the protocol View is probably
the poster child for doing this.
And we're gonna see more about View
in a couple of slides here.
In addition to adding functions,
like registerWithDMV, you
can also use an extension
to protocol if you want to
add default implementations.
So here I am extending Moveable
and I'm actually providing
a default implementation
for hasMoved as hasMoved
is one of the vars
in the protocol
but I'm providing a default
implementation here.
I'm just looking at my
distance from start,
and if that's greater than zero,
I'm gonna assume I've moved.
And I'm doing this with
an extension to Moveable.
So this makes it possible
for me then to have a struct,
I have one here called
ChessPiece which is a Moveable,
you can move chess pieces.
ChessPiece does not need
to implement hasMoved.
If ChessPiece just implements moveBy
and distanceFromStart,
then it will have successfully
implemented Moveable
because it'll pick up the
default implementation
from that extension right there.
Now, if ChessPiece wanted to
implement hasMoved itself,
it could, but it doesn't have to
because there's a default implementation
for hasMoved in that extension.
Now, you can use extensions of course,
to add code to structs
and classes as well,
not just protocols.
So here, for example, I
have a struct called Boat
and it's got its own methods,
whatever they might be.
And here I'm adding extension to Boat,
a function sailAroundTheWorld.
And this extension, you
can see, has curly braces,
it has an implementation.
This is an actual implementation
of sailAroundTheWorld
that we've added to Boat.
You can even make something
like a Boat conformed
to a protocol purely by
using your extension.
So Boat doesn't implement
any protocols right now
but I can make Boat implement Moveable
by having the extension to Boat
that says colon Moveable
and then in that extension,
implement moveBy and distanceFromStart.
Now Boat is a Moveable.
And I added it totally with extension.
It's not an uncommon thing to do
to take a structure or
class and make it conformed
to a protocol using purely an extension,
or you add the code in an extension.
Why do we do all this protocol stuff?
Now, for those of you who are coming
from object oriented programming,
this was gonna seem like,
what's going on here?
Why do we do this?
Well, there's a really
good conceptual reason
why we're doing this.
Protocols are away for
types, structs and classes,
other protocols, even enums,
which we haven't talked about,
to say what they are capable of,
what functions they can do,
what vars they have on them,
and it's also a way for other code
to demand certain behavior
from other objects
by demanding that they
conform to a protocol,
either by having a variable of that type
that they're trying to assign
or parameter to a function.
And there's even other
mechanisms you're gonna see soon
when we talk about generics and protocols
for demanding that you want
that thing to be a Moveable.
It has to be a Vehicle, whatever.
You can demand it now that
you have this protocol.
But in all of that,
neither side has to reveal
what sort of structure class you are.
You completely can be anything you want.
You just say you implement Moveable
and now you can be
operated on as a Moveable,
but you could be anything.
You could be a Car, you
could be a PortableThing.
You could be a Boat.
We know when neither side cares.
All one side cares is that
you can do the Moveable things
and all the other side cares is that
it implement all those Moveable things.
So this is what functional programming,
or really we might call it,
protocol-oriented programming,
is all about.
It's about formalizing how data structures
in our application
function, how they behaved.
Even when we talk about vars
in the context of protocols,
we don't define how
they're stored or computed,
we don't even say where
we just talk about whether
they're read only or read, write.
And through all this we
focus on the functionality.
We're hiding the implementation details.
It's kind of the ultimate promise
of encapsulation from
object-oriented programming
but it's really taken to a higher level
because it doesn't mix it inexorably
with the data and all that,
it's just talking about the functionality.
And all of this gets even more powerful
when we combine it with generics.
Protocols plus generics equals,
as I say here, super powers.
So let's look at how generics,
remember that's the don't care stuff
that we talked about last time,
how it combines with protocols
to make super powers.
Here we go.
Let's do this by example.
Let's say I had a
protocol called Greatness,
and this protocol only
has one function in it
which is, isGreaterThan other.
One argument other to this
function isGreaterThan.
By the way, this is kind
of an interesting function
because the type of
other is capital S Self.
That's a special kind of
name of a type in a protocol
which means the actual type
that's implementing this protocol,
because remember, protocols themselves
have no implementation,
they get implemented
by structs and classes.
So that Self means that
the actual structure class
that implements this, that
is executing it at the time.
So that's kind of cool.
And I'm gonna show you how that works
in just a few clicks here.
So if we have this protocol,
look at what we can do.
Extension Array, so I'm
adding something to Array,
where the element, the
don't care of the Array,
conforms to Greatness, colon Greatness.
So that where I put in red
because it's really the key part
of connecting generics and protocols.
Here, I'm actually going to add a var,
or I could do it with functions,
but I'm gonna add a var here
to Array so that every
Array where the element,
the don't care, conforms to
Greatness will get this var.
Let that sink in.
Now, this var will not exist in Arrays
where the don't cares don't implement
the protocol Greatness.
This var just will not be there.
If you tried to type it in your code,
the compiler would say,
this Array does not implement greatest
It would only say it implements greatest
only lets you type that in without error
if it was an Array of something
that implements the protocol Greatness
Now I like to call this,
we care a little bit.
Normally we call generics don't care,
element is a don't care,
Array doesn't care what's inside of it.
Well, this is kind of,
this extension to Array cares
a little bit about element.
It doesn't really care what element is,
can be any struct or class, but we do care
that it implements Greatness.
So this is care a little bit,
you wanna think of it that way.
Then this var greatness, look
what its type is, element.
It's the don't care because I'm gonna look
through the Array and find
the one that's the greatest
by calling isGreaterThan other
on all of the things in the Array
which I know I can do because
this extension to Array
is only where the elements
implement Greatness.
See how it all works here?
So you can easily imagine, I'm
not gonna show the code here,
but you can easily imagine
building a for loop
that just goes through all the elements,
calls isGreaterThan on all of them,
figures out which one is the greatest
and that's just returns it.
So let's see how we would
use an Array like this.
Let's imagine that I use another extension
to make Int the type Int
which is a struct, implement Greatness.
No problem, it's really easy
to implement an Int isGreaterThan other,
is just self isGreaterThan other Ints,
you can just use greater than
to see if something is
greater than something else.
But imagine I had some
totally different type.
Here's extension of President.
That's the president of the United States.
I'm gonna make it implement Greatness,
func isGreaterThan other President.
And I'm gonna implement...
Actually, I had Donald Trump,
guest iOS programmer come
in and implement this one.
He says that isGreaterThan
is just self.name equals Trump.
If that's true, then of
course isGreaterThan,
he's a great iOS programmer,
everybody tells me that,
I hear that everywhere.
So here we go, we got this.
Now, one thing I wanna point out
about this slide that you're seeing
is the stuff in purple here.
Remember that isGreaterThan
other Self at the top?
Remember that capital S Self?
Look how, when I've
created these extensions,
that self has turned into
the type I'm extending,
the type I'm implementing
this protocol with.
Hopefully that helps
you understand the Self.
I bring this up because
there's quite a few protocols
in Swift UI that do this
where they have a var
or a function that one of the types
of the arguments is the
thing implementing this.
So this is not uncommon.
So now I have Int and President.
They both implement this
protocol, Greatness.
So I should be able to call
that Array var on them.
I should be able to use Array var
that I defined right there,
greatest, to get the greatest.
So let's see what that looks like for Int.
So for Int, let's say
I have a numbersArray,
it's an Array of Int that's its type.
I'm going to set it equal
to a constant Array here,
we saw that in the demo.
We were doing it with the emojis.
Here, I'm doing with the
numbers three, seven and 42,
so it's just an Array of
that and now I can say,
let foo equals the numbersArray.greatest.
And that compiles and works because Int is
what's in that Array and Int implements
the Greatness protocol so the greatest var
is defined therefore.
And so foo will be 42 here
'cause we do implement it
by just saying greater.
And I can do exactly the same thing
if I had a President in this Array.
Let's say the struct
President can be created
with the name of the president.
So I create some Array of Presidents here.
Now, I'm gonna say let foo equal
the presidentsArray.greatest.
And that's going to give me back foo
or foo whose name is Trump,
of course, based on the
code that he wrote here.
So hopefully this is
making it clear to you
how we use generics
and protocols together.
And we're gonna do this all
over the place in SwiftUI.
Some of you are looking at all this,
and I'm sure you're
shivering, as I say here.
You gotta be thinking, holy cow,
how am I supposed to be expected to know
how to design my code
using this technology?
I mean, this is just all new to me.
And this is indeed a
very powerful foundation
for designing things, very powerful.
But functional programming
does require some mastery
that only comes with experience.
And the good news is that
you can do a lot of stuff
in SwiftUI, most things,
without really mastering
functional programming.
But here you are at Stanford
trying to get a good education.
And so the reason I'm
explaining this to you now
is so that the more you use it in SwiftUI,
the more you see it in the documentation
where you see these wares happening,
we see protocols like View
and Identifiable coming down the road,
that you're not just saying,
I have to put colon View here,
you're actually understanding
how it's being designed underneath.
And the more you see it,
the more it's gonna sink in
and the more eventually you
might start to be capable
of doing functional
programming design as well.
But no one expects you, right now,
to be able to be designing stuff
where you're adding
extensions to protocols
with generics and all that.
But eventually you'll be able to.
And in the meantime you'll kind of know
what's going on in SwiftUI.
So I'm just putting this one
slide up here about enum,
but once again, not gonna talk
about enum in this lecture.
We'll talk about it soon, not to worry.
So that pretty much
covers what we're going
to talk about today on architecture
and we're almost there in
covering this entire topic.
And now I'm gonna shift gears entirely
and go to a completely
different topic which is layout,
in other words, how do we decide
where all our Views go on screen?
The way that SwiftUI does
this is amazingly simple.
It's one of the more elegant
things in all of SwiftUI.
There's really only three
steps to doing this.
The first one is the container Views,
like HStacks and VStacks
and things like that.
They offer space to the Views
that are inside of them.
And then those Views choose
a size for themselves,
what they want to be.
Based on that offer,
they could choose a
size same as the offer,
that's the most common,
they can choose a size
smaller than the offer,
they could choose a size that's
larger even than the offer.
So they use, in a very kind
of good encapsulation way,
Views decide what size
they're going to be.
No one tells them what size to be.
We just offer them space, they decide.
But then after that, the
container Views like the stacks,
it's their job to position their
Views inside of themselves.
And that's it, these are the three steps
to get everything laid out in SwiftUI.
So let's dive into this a little bit.
Let's talk about container Views.
So the most common container View
that you're already familiar
with is HStack and VStack.
Of course, there's Zstack as well
that kind of stacks them
on top of each other,
but HStack and VStack are interesting
in that they divide up the
space that's offered to them
amongst all of their subviews.
And we'll talk about how
that works in a moment.
ForEach is kind of an
unusual container View.
It actually defers the positioning
and sizing to the container that it's in,
that's why we put our CardViews
that were in that ForEach into an HStack.
So their ForEach is deferring
letting the HStack decide.
And a hidden thing that's going
on with layout is modifiers,
like dot padding and others.
They essentially contain
the View that they modify,
if you wanna think of it that way,
and some of them, like padding, do layout.
So let's talk a little bit more in detail
about HStack and VStack,
the most important one
or at least the one that's
doing the most layout.
The way that the stacks
divide up the space
that they're offered is
kind of divided equally
and then they offer it to the
least flexible Views first.
So what do we mean by that?
So an example of a very space
inflexible View is Image.
So we haven't talked about image yet
but it's just a View that shows an image,
as you might imagine.
And of course it wants to
be the size of that image,
pretty inflexible in that way.
So generally the Images are gonna get
the space they want first.
Another example of a
pretty inflexible View,
not quite as inflexible as Image, is Text.
Text always wants to size itself
to fit the text inside
of it understandably
but it does have a way to
be a little bit smaller
and put dot dot dot at the end of the text
as we'll talk about in a second here.
So it's not quite as
inflexible as an Image.
And most Views are very flexible.
For example, all the Shapes,
like RoundedRectangle that we saw,
whatever size you offer it,
it's pretty much gonna take that
and it's going to draw itself
appropriately in that size.
So after one of these
Views chooses its own size
and takes whatever size it wants,
that size is removed from the space
that the stack is trying to allocate
and then it goes on to the
next least flexible Views
and rinse and repeat until
all the space is used up.
So it's as simple as that.
That's how HStack and VStack
apportion, their space.
Now, after all the Views
have chosen their size
then the HStack and VStack
sizes itself to fit those Views
with whatever little spacing
in between that it provides.
HStack and VStack work
with any View, of course,
but there's a couple of them
that I'm gonna introduce to you here
that really help with layout.
One of them is called Spacer.
So a Spacer is just a View
that takes all of the space
that's offered to it.
So if you give it space,
it's gonna use that space.
And so it's used for filling in space.
Now it doesn't actually draw anything,
it just kind of uses up
space in an HStack or VStack,
that's why it's called a Spacer.
It has that minLength argument
which is the minimum
size that it should be
in the direction we're
laying out horizontally
or vertically, depending on
whether it's HStack or VStack,
although we usually don't specify
because the default for
that is the right amount
of space on this platform.
One thing that you're gonna start
to get used to as the quarter goes on,
that even though we're focusing on iOS,
you can use SwiftUI on
Apple Watch and Apple TV
and the spacing and the
layout is a little different
on these platforms.
And SwiftUI is really smart about saying,
I'm on an Apple watch so I'm
gonna use this much space
in my Spacer by default or whatever.
So that's why we really wanna
try and use these default
and not specify minLength
when we use Spacer.
Same thing with spacing
on the HStack itself,
HStack spacing.
And we don't wanna do that.
Even padding, generally
it's fine to put padding
but if you start putting numbers in there
and specifying exact paddings like we saw,
you're defeating a little bit
of the purpose of this
platform independence.
Now, sometimes you need it, you just do
but we try to use these
defaults as much as possible.
So another cool View to put in an HStack
or VStack is Divider.
So Divider just draws a dividing line,
again, platform specific,
it depends what a divider looks like
in the context that it's in.
Of course, the Divider
is not like a Spacer,
it doesn't use all up all that space.
It only uses enough
space to draw that line.
And the line obviously goes
opposite to the direction
that we're laying out.
So for an HStack, the
divider is obviously gonna be
a vertical line, and for a VStack,
it's gonna be a horizontal line.
So you're almost certainly
gonna want to use one
or both of these in your
next homework assignment.
And they're really valuable
for doing layout with stacks.
These HStacks and VStacks,
I told you that they're kind of choosing
which of its Views to offer
space to next priority wise
using this least flexible thing,
but you can actually override that
with this View modifier layoutPriority.
So here's an example of an HStack
that has a Text that's really important.
It's got an Image which we
know is very not flexible,
and so normally would get a
lot of attention from HStack.
And then it has another Text
which is less important.
So I've added the View
modifier dot layoutPriority 100
which I can pick any
number I want there really,
it doesn't matter, it's
a floating point number.
And that's more than the
default layoutPriority
which is zero.
So when this HStack
goes to offer its space,
it's going to offer this Text space first.
And that Text is gonna say,
well, sure, I wanna be this big
so I can fit this word,
important, all the way.
Then it's gonna say, okay,
well there's no other high priority ones.
There could be other ones
with different numbers.
It starts with the highest
priority and goes down.
And so now it goes to do the Image
because that's less
flexible than the Text,
Image gets it space and then
the unimportant text has
to fit itself into the space remaining.
And as we mentioned before,
when a Text doesn't get enough space,
it will put dot dot dot in there to elide
or shorten the text to
fit the space it did get.
It always wants to be its space.
It never wants to be larger
than its text fits in.
It always wants to be the exact size
but if it's forced to be smaller,
it knows how to do dot dot dot.
Another and significant part of HStack
and VStack's layout is their alignment.
So imagine you have a VStack,
a vertical stack of Views.
And what if those Views
pick their own size
and they're not the same width.
So they can't all be kind
of filling the whole width
of this vertical stack.
So does the VStack left align them
or center them or right align them?
How does it know where to put them?
Well, there's actually an
argument to VStack and HStack.
We already know that VStack
and HStack have the argument spacing
which determines the
spacing between the Views.
It also has another argument, alignment.
And alignment takes an
alignment guide as its argument.
And one of the alignment
guides, for example, is leading.
Now, why leading here instead of left?
If I just want this VStack
to have all of these be left aligned,
why don't I say dot left?
And in fact, there's no
such thing as dot left.
And dot leading means to have the things
in the VStack line up so
that their edges start
from where text comes from.
In different languages
sometimes the text comes
from the right and moves to the left,
like Hebrew and Arabic.
So we want our VStacks
to generally match up
with that text coming from that side.
Text baselines can also be lined up.
So HStacks, well, it only
makes sense in an HStack.
You can line it up so that
the bottom of the text,
even if they're different
fonts, will all be lined up.
For those of you know about
fonts, there are two baselines.
I'm not gonna talk about that
but you can line up with
the first text baseline
or the second text
baseline in your HStack.
You can even define your own things
to line up alignment guides.
And that's a little beyond
the scope of this course.
So we're just gonna use the
built in ones like dot center
which is usually the default alignment is
to center the thing in the middle
of the VStack or the HStack.
But there's also top
and bottom trailing
leading all these things.
As you can imagine, when
you just start typing
in an Xcode, VStack alignment colon,
of course, Xcode will
help you and tell you
what all those built-ins are.
That's it for stacks.
Stacks are very important.
But there's this other thing, modifiers,
like dot padding, that I said kind of act
like essentially container Views.
Remember that these things,
dot padding, et cetera,
they return a View.
And you might've thought
they just return a View
so that we could then send them another,
call another function on
them, dot foregroundColor
and then that gives us a View back,
we call dot padding on that.
And that gives us a View back
and call dot font on that.
So it's not just to give us a View back
so we can call another function on it.
Those Views that come back
might actually be participating
in the layout.
Now, most of them don't participate,
like font and foregroundColor.
They're not affecting layouts
so any space they're offered
by an HStack or some other container,
they're just gonna pass it on
to whatever View they contain.
For the purposes of this
slide, we're gonna think
of a View that these modifiers
modify as being contained
by that View that the modifier
returns which it kind of is.
We're gonna see how these View
modifiers are made next week,
probably, or the week after,
depending on how things go.
And you'll see that kind of really
what's happening is that it's containing
the View it's modifying.
What about these modifiers
that actually participate
in the layout process like padding.
Let's look at padding.
The View that's returned by
dot padding, this modifier,
it offers the View that
it's modifying a space
that's the same size as was offered to it
but reduced by 10 points in this case,
whatever the padding is.
It might be if that 10 is not there,
then it would be whatever
system appropriate padding.
It's essentially removing that 10
because it knows it's
supposed to provide the 10.
And then that View that's returned
by padding chooses its own size
to be whatever size the thing
that it's modifying
ended up being plus 10.
So that's what padding does,
it adds 10 points around the outside
or whatever edges you say.
Another thing is modifying.
So you see how dot padding
modifier is just a View
that participates in the layout.
What's another example of this?
You've already used it in your homework,
dot aspectRatio.
The View that's returned by
dot aspectRatio modifier,
it takes the space offered to it
and it picks a size for itself
that's either smaller
than that offered size
and has the aspect ratio,
that's if we choose the dot
fit option of aspectRatio,
or it could be bigger than
the size that's offered to it,
that's the dot fill option that
uses all the offered space.
And so yes, it is possible
when you're a View,
when you're offered a
certain amount of space,
you can choose your size to be larger.
Now that's rare.
We don't generally want
Views kind of spilling out
all over each other, but it makes sense,
like in this aspectRatio
fill, maybe that makes sense.
So then the aspectRatio
View that's now sized itself
to have that aspect ratio,
offers the space that it chose
to whatever View it's
modifying, like our CardView.
So our CardView fits itself then
in that nice aspect ratio space.
So let's see an example
of a full layout happening
in the size being passed
around and things like that.
So here's an HStack
similar to the one we have
in our Memorize game, not exactly the same
but very very similar.
How is the space for
this thing apportioned?
Well, the first thing to understand is
that the first View that's
gonna be offered the space
into which this whole green
thing goes is that padding View.
It's the outermost View.
It's actually the View that
is this whole thing in the end
but it's gonna be offered
whatever space is available
for this whole green construct here.
Now what it's going to
do, it's going to reduce,
take 10 points, off the edges of it
and pass that space that's
left onto the next View
which is the View returned by
the foregroundColor modifier.
Now that modifier isn't really
participating in the layout,
doesn't really have any effect on the size
and position the thing,
so it just passes that on
untouched to the HStack.
Now, the HStack, as we know,
is big time layout View.
It's going to divide up its
space starting out equally
and since the aspectRatios
aren't things like Images
or Texts that are fixed sizes,
it's going to end up
dividing the space equally
among all of the aspectRatio
Views in the ForEach,
because we know the
ForEach itself just defers
to the HStack.
So it's the aspectRatio Views now
that are being laid out in HStack.
Each aspectRatio View is
going to set its width
to be its share of the HStack's width
and then pick a height that
matches the aspect ratio,
the 2/3 aspect ratio, or if
the height is limited here,
it might be the other way around
where the aspectRatio View takes all
of the height it's offered
and instead chooses a width
that's less to fit.
So it could go either way.
It depends on whichever is gonna fit best
in the space that is offered.
Then the aspectRatio has picked that size.
It's going to offer that to the CardView
and the CardView is going
to use all of the space
because it's like a normal View,
whatever space you offer it,
pretty much it's going to use.
After all this offering
and sizing happens,
what's going to be the size
of this whole green View?
Well, it's gonna be the size
of whatever View.padding 10 returns
which is the result of
the HStack sizing itself
to fit all those aspectRatio Views
plus 10 points on all sides.
That's gonna be the size
of this whole green thing.
Let's talk about Views
that take all the space
that's offered to them.
Obviously things like RoundedRectangle,
it's real easy for them.
They just crawl around a
rectangle all the way to the edges
of what they're offered.
But what about custom Views like CardView?
CardView we built out of a ZStack
with RoundedRectangle, Texts,
we're building this thing.
It takes all the space
that's offered to it,
and there's no reason it shouldn't,
but it should really be adapting itself
to whatever space was offered.
And we really see this desperately
with the font size of the emoji.
And in your homework I asked you
for really small cards to
switch to a smaller font.
And I'm sure you'll probably realize,
wow, this is a really bad
solution to this problem.
And of course it is.
Really, what we need to do and
we're gonna do in our demo,
is pick a font size that is related
to the size that were offered.
Since we're gonna accept
the size offered to us,
we should pick this
font size that fits it.
So how does a View know
what space was offered to it
and can make that font
choosing decision, for example?
Well, we do that with a special View.
It's just a View, but
it is kind of special,
called GeometryReader.
And what you do with a GeometryReader View
is it wraps around whatever
thing that you want
to adapt to the size.
And so this would normally just
take whatever's in your body
and you just wrap GeometryReader
around it like this.
GeometryReader is just a View.
And I'm not showing you
the obvious thing here.
GeometryReader, open parentheses, content,
colon, all this, just like
in HStack or whatever,
this is just the content.
But you do notice that it
has a little argument there
geometry in, similar to
how ForEach has an argument
which is the thing we're iterating over.
This also has an argument.
So this argument is of type GeometryProxy.
And this GeometryProxy is just a struct
and it has some nice information in there,
the most important of which
is the first one you see,
var size, that is the
size you're being offered.
The width and height CGSize
is a width and height
that you're being offered.
And you can use that size, it's in points,
and of course font sizes are in points.
So it's gonna be pretty easy for us
to pick a font size that
fits nicely in that size.
You see some other things here,
like the frame is
actually not only the size
but it's a rectangle where we are
in a certain coordinate space like
our parents coordinate space
or the global coordinate space
we can even look at if we like.
And I'm gonna talk about
the last one there,
safeAreaInsets, on the next slide.
One thing to remember
about GeometeryReader,
it's just a View but it always accepts
the space offered to it.
And I underline that because
it requires a little sinking in
because you don't wanna get
into a recursive loop here
where the GeometryReader
is reading its size
and then you're trying to
actually change the size
of the GeometryReader based
on the size that it read.
It doesn't work that way.
GeometryReaders always
accept the size, the space,
that's offered to them,
you have to think of it that way.
So GeometryReaders utility is just limited
to knowing what size you're being offered
and adjusting how you look on the inside,
that's what GeometryReader is for.
Don't try to twist GeometryReader
into something it's not.
It's just reading your geometry.,
it's called GeometryReader,
it reads the geometry
and you adapt to it so
you can change your font
and things like that.
The safe area thing that we mentioned,
that safeAreaInsets
that the GeometryReader tells you about.
The safe area is best
visualized by thinking
of the notch on the iPhone 10.
Most of the time, you
don't wanna be drawing up
on the size where the notch is up there,
not always though.
Sometimes you might actually
wanna draw up there.
And there's other safe area things too.
Sometimes Views will add adornments
or the way they kind of draw on screen
where they don't want you
drawing in certain spaces
so they kind of create this
safe area for you to draw in.
But if you wanna go outside
your safe area, you can,
and the way you do that is
by the View modifier here
edgesIgnoringSafeArea,
and you specify which edges that you want
to ignore that safe area.
So if I say edgesIgnoringSafeArea top,
then that ZStack and
everything in it is going
to ignore that there's
a safe area on the top
and just draw right up
underneath that notch up there.
And so it could be photo
viewing app or something,
maybe you wanna go all
the way to the edges
so you can do that here.
Let's talk a little bit about
how containers do what they do
which is offer space to their
Views and then position them.
It offers space with this modifier frame.
Now, I'm not gonna talk
about frame in detail here.
You can go look at the documentation frame
has quite a lot of arguments, you know,
ideal width, minimum width,
all of these kinds of things
to try and communicate to the
Views here is where the space
that I'm offering you.
So that's all for space.
And then once the View
has chosen its own size,
then we're gonna use
this modifier position
to put it somewhere in
our coordinate space
before the container.
So that's how they do that.
Pretty straightforward.
Stacks, for example, would use
their alignment information
and the spacing and all that
to figure out where their Views should go,
and it would set this CGPoint
which is the center of
the Views, at the CGPoint
for each of the Views.
By the way, it's kind of a
cool little modifier here
called offset which will offset the View
from wherever container put it.
So you can let the container do its job,
put the thing somewhere
and then you can still offset
it a little bit by something.
And the container could do this
but also someone else could do it.
The View could do it to itself.
I wanna be offset by a little bit.
So offset is kind of a fun little one.
We don't use offset that much
but I just wanna let you know it's there.
Now, for Memorize, we're
gonna use frame and position
to create our own container View
which is kind of like a stack.
It's gonna be called a Grid
and it's 2D, rows and columns,
instead of just a horizontal row
which is a pretty sad looking game,
if I do say so myself right now.
And we obviously want that
to be rows and columns.
We'll do that by using frame and position
to create our own container.
So we're gonna go back to the demo today.
I'd love to have time to
actually go do that container,
but we don't have that,
end of lecture three here.
I do have a short demo
though I'm going to do
just to show you how GeometryReader works.
And what we're gonna do is
what I've been talking about,
make our font, our emoji font, size better
to the space we're offered
using a GeometryReader.
While I'm there, I may
do a quick little thing
where I'm gonna show you the best way
or the kind of way we've all agreed on
to collect magic numbers in our code.
If you already have one in
there like cornerRadius 10,
that 10 is a magic number,
it really shouldn't be
embedded in our code.
There's kind of a canonical way in Swift
to take that out and put
it in its own little space
so it's well-documented and typed.
Now we'll start our next lecture though,
using GeometryReader and
also generics with protocols
and functions as types
to make this beautiful
little simple Grid View
that's just gonna be like an HStack.
We're gonna replace our HStack
by just using this Grid View
and make our cards be in a nice grid.
So let's hop into that demo
and then that'll be the
end of this lecture.
Now in your homework, you were asked
to adjust the font choice here
to fit really small cards
because small cards,
the font we chose,
large title was too big.
And that might have fixed
it just for small cards
but I made you do that almost to realize,
well, that's no good solution,
especially when we're in landscape
where even large title is way too small.
So what we really want is for our card
to pick a font that uses all the space.
That's really what we wanna do.
So how are we going to do that?
Well, we're gonna do
that with a special View.
It's another View, just
like HStack is a View
and ForEach is a View and
ZStack is a few, Text is a View.
These are all just Views.
There's a special View that is called
the GeometryReader View.
So GeometryReader has one argument
which is the content that it's going
to display inside of itself
which is just another View like our card,
the ZStack that will make our card,
but it has a nice argument
here called geometry,
just like ForEach was a View
that had an argument here
but it also had this content argument
and it provided the Card that
it was iterating through.
Same thing here,
GeometryReader, it has content,
asks for a View but it
provides this special geometry.
And we're gonna look
at this little variable
that is given to you inside here
'cause we can look at this and see
what the size of our View is.
Now notice that when we
put our code, our ZStack,
inside of a GeometryReader content,
we got these requires self dot thing.
So to go through here and
do a fix out of this one,
fix that one as well, pick that up.
So what is this?
Let's take a look at the
documentation for GeometryReader.
So I'm gonna do Option + click
to look at GeometryReader.
And you can see here
struct GeometryReader.
It's got a don't care called Content
where that Content is a View.
And so now, hopefully, you are starting
to understand what that means,
where Content is a View, right?
Content is a don't care,
View is a protocol.
So we've turned that don't care into a,
well we care a little bit, right?
We care that the Content of
a GeometryReader is a View,
but otherwise it can be anything it wants.
And so I'm gonna open
that in the documentation
and take a look, see what it says.
And here's the init.
You can see that it takes
this one argument content
which actually you should be
recognizing this syntax here
because really, it takes a function
that returns this Content don't care,
which we know is actually a
we care a little bit Content
where Content colon View so
we know it has to be a View.
And so that's a function,
function that takes an argument,
GeometryProxy, and returns
this don't care Content.
Don't worry about that @escaping there.
We'll be talking about
that in the weeks to come.
So let's click on this GeometryProxy
and see its decoration.
Here it is, and you can see it has
the things we talked about in the slides.
Now I'm gonna focus obviously
on the size right here.
So let's click on that.
And you can see that
size is just a CGSize,
it's get only, it's read only.
It's just going to tell
us the width and height
that we've been offered
to draw this View in.
So that's exactly what we want.
We want this geometry size right here.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna have
my CardView take ownership
for setting its own font right here.
So it's gonna go to font.
So I'm no longer setting
the font in the game itself.
I'm letting the Card set its own font
which is probably better
encapsulation anyway.
Why we're here, of course,
we don't need this colon
content thing just like HStack
and all these other things.
We can get rid of that and get rid of that
so this looks a lot cleaner there.
So we wanna do a font
here, so write some font,
whose size is based on that geometry size.
So I'm gonna create a system font,
just different ways to make
the system font right here,
styles and sizes.
So I'm just gonna pick size.
I want a CGFloat with
the size, the point size.
And remember the point
size of font is related
to the point width and
the point height there.
So I'm actually gonna pick the minimum
of the width to the height
'cause I don't necessarily want to depend
on knowing what my aspect ratio here is.
And so I'm just gonna pick
the minimum of those two
to make sure that I pick a font that fits.
So that's min geometry size width
and the geometry size height.
So I'm using that size var that we saw
that's in this GeometryProxy right here.
And maybe we could just try this.
Let's just pick a font size
that is the minimum of these two
and just see what this looks like.
So let's run this.
Look at that.
So that is a much closer size
and you even got smaller.
But this is actually a little too big.
It's got a little too big there.
Maybe that's just because plot point sizes
aren't exactly the width of the font.
It may probably closer
related to the height,
but also we do put a little
stroke around the edge
that takes away a little space as well.
So probably I need some sort
of constant multiplier here,
like maybe times 75%,
0.75, something like that.
And 75% actually looks pretty good.
Looks good when it's big,
looks good when it's small.
Before we finish up lecture three,
I wanna take just a moment here
to talk about a coding style issue.
I don't often talk too
much about coding style,
purely for time constraints
in these lectures
but this time I am going to mention this.
'cause it's a little bit of a segue
into how we're going to
structure our View code
to make it as readable as possible.
This problem I'm worried
about is these magic numbers.
We've created these blue magic numbers
and started to sprinkle them
out throughout our code.
That's not very good coding style.
SwiftUI is declarative.
We're essentially declaring
the UI directly here.
We're not calling functions
to tell it to build itself,
we are declaring it right here.
And when we do that,
these blue numbers end up
being kind of the knobs that we can turn
to fine tune the way our View
looks and get it just right.
Well, right now our knobs
are just spread all over the place here.
Really nice if we could
have a control panel.
So I'm going to create
a little control panel.
I'm gonna comment here to
MARK it drawing constants,
I'm gonna call it,
and put all my drawing constants down here
as just vars and lets and
functions on my struct.
And this idea of putting vars and lets
and functions in your struct
to clean up or fix magic numbers
in your View, really important.
You're gonna see that
most Views have a few vars
and lets and funcs down here
to make this look as clean and
understandable as possible.
So let's use this idea to get
these magic numbers out here.
These happened to be constants.
So I'm gonna use let.
Remember, let is like var except
for let means it's a constant.
So let's do the corner radius
up there, cornerRadius.
You might think you could
say cornerRadius equals 10
but this doesn't work and
I'm gonna show you why here.
If you hold down the option key, remember,
and click, it'll tell you the declaration
of this thing that you clicked on.
In our case, it's our cornerRadius
and it has been typed as an Int.
Remember that if we say
let a var equal something
and we don't specify it's
type, Swift will infer it.
And here it's looking at this 10
and referring, looks like an Int.
That's not what we want.
All of these blue numbers
in here are CGFloats,
floating point numbers we use to draw.
Now, I can't even just say 10.0.
If I do that and Option +
click, it thinks it's a Double.
These are not double precision
floating point numbers.
This Double struct is not
the same as a CGFloat struct.
So I have to explicitly
type this, CGFloat.
And that's not necessarily
that burdensome or onerous,
it's kind of nice in
a way to remind myself
these are drawing constants down here.
Let's do our other ones.
We got the edgeLineWidth.
There's another constant we have up there,
that number three, and of
course we have this .75
which is really like a
scaling factor for our fonts.
I'm gonna call it fontScaleFactor,
that's also a CGFloat, 0.75.
Now that I have these down here,
I can replace all my
magic numbers with these
and this becomes the
knobs on my control panel.
So let's do that.
We've got this one.
I'm gonna copy and paste,
make this go a little quicker.
And over here, this three
is this edge line right here
and our fontScaleFactor
here is this .75 here.
This is nice.
This actually makes this
code read nicely as well,
pretty much like the English language,
trying to understand what's going on.
However, you notice it's introduced
a whole slew of errors here.
They're actually all the same error.
It's the dreaded explicit self dot
to make capture semantics explicit.
And we could just, maybe fix this one
and click here and then fix this one
and I click it and fix it,
but I'm gonna show you
a trick for avoiding
this self dot thing in this
common case of GeometryReader.
So whenever you do a GeometryReader,
the stuff inside is always gonna complain
about this self dot.
By the way, same thing with ForEach.
ForEach stuff inside is gonna
complain about self dot.
Not every View does that
but those two do and
they're commonly used.
I'm gonna create a func
which I'm gonna call
body for size, CGSize,
and it's gonna return my body,
so that's gonna be some View just like
I can have some View be
the type of this var,
I can have some View be the
return type of this func.
And I'm gonna put my body,
to cut it out of here,
and put it in here, and
then just call this function
in my GeometryReader, self.body
for the geometry size.
This code cleaned up
actually kind of nicely.
This makes perfect sense.
And this code now is no longer embedded
inside this GeometryReader like this
so you don't need these self dot.
So I can get rid of that one and that one
and that one and this one.
All those self dots are gone.
What's more here, I didn't
pass the entire geometry
to this body, just the
size, the geometry size var.
So down here, I don't
need to say geometry.size.
This geometry.size is now just size,
this size that I passed in.
So that made this code look a lot nicer
and I almost always recommend,
at least for the next couple of months
until they put that Swift
self dot change in there
so the self dot is not
causing this problem anymore.
This is a real clean way
to have this code not have
to worry about self dot.
And you can do the same thing
body for item in a ForEach
'cause ForEach is gonna cause
that self dot problem as well.
We could do one other thing here.
Here, I could have a func
for the font size called
fontSize for size,
have it return a font size
which is also a CGFloat,
and put this code right here down in here
so that this just reads fontSize for size.
You might think this is
a very simple expression,
I don't really need to turn
it into its own func here,
but again, you can't make this too simple.
You really want to have
this be simple as possible.
And sometimes you're
forced to make it simple.
These ifs, as I explained,
can't be arbitrarily complex expressions.
So sometimes this needs to be a function
that returns a Bool, not in this case,
'cause this is simple Bool.
But making these little
one liner functions
that make this body look
cleaner, very common.
Here, we might even not have
to have this fontScaleFactor
be its own separate let
because you can kind of
think of the font size
as just part of the drawing constants.
This is the constant font
size for a given size.
So that's it for lecture three.
And we're gonna dive right back in,
start with lecture four
and continue with this demo
and make our HStack up here be a 2D grid.
We're gonna learn a lot
of stuff doing that.
- [Narrator] For more, please
visit us at stanford.edu.